<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Coding with Data</title>
    <link>/tags/python/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Coding with Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A tidy text analysis of Rick and Morty</title>
      <link>/blog/a-tidy-text-analysis-of-rick-and-morty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 23:15:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/a-tidy-text-analysis-of-rick-and-morty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/a841k9g.gif&#34; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
pre code, pre, code {
  white-space: pre !important;
  overflow-x: scroll !important;
  word-break: keep-all !important;
  word-wrap: initial !important;
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;adventures-in-the-multiverse&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Adventures in the multiverse&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those unfamiliar with the show, Rick and Morty is an animated series about the interuniversal exploits of a half-drunk mad scientist Rick, and his daft grandson Morty. Living under one roof with his daughter, Rick constantly drags his grandson Morty along for adventures into unusual worlds inhabited by surreal creatures. At first hesitant to accompany his eccentric granddad, Morty slowly grows into an indispensable sidekick. Using Rick’s portal gun, they leave the rest of their dysfunctional family at home, and travel through space and time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most episodes draw inspiration from or make fun of cult movies such as Back to the Future, A Nightmare on Elm Street, Inception and many other classics by the likes of John Carpenter or David Cronenberg. Besides the ruthless humor and over-the-top visual scenery, the show brilliantly builds independent sci-fi realms, going about their day-to-day according to their wacky rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;one-mans-weekend-project-another-mans-treasure&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;One man’s weekend project, another man’s treasure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading the book &lt;a href=&#34;http://tidytextmining.com/&#34;&gt;Tidy Text Mining&lt;/a&gt; online, I have been wanting to try out some of the concepts outlined in the book, and the functions of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/juliasilge/tidytext&#34;&gt;accompanying package&lt;/a&gt;, on an interesting dataset. So I was pretty stoked to find &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fkeck/subtools&#34;&gt;Francois Keck’s &lt;strong&gt;subtools package&lt;/strong&gt; on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, that allows for reading &lt;em&gt;.srt&lt;/em&gt; files (the usual format for subtitles) straight into R. With season 3 of Rick and Morty coming to an end last week, the stars have finally aligned to roll up my sleeves and have some fun with text mining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is very easy to find English subtitles for pretty much anything on the Internet. With subtools, an entire series can be read with one command from the containing folder, &lt;code&gt;read.subtitles.serie()&lt;/code&gt;. We convert the resulting MultiSubtitles object to a data.frame with a second command &lt;code&gt;subDataFrame()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(subtools)
a &amp;lt;- read.subtitles.serie(dir = &amp;quot;/series/rick and morty/&amp;quot;)
df &amp;lt;- subDataFrame(a)
str(df)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## Read: 3 seasons, 31 episodes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## &amp;#39;data.frame&amp;#39;:    16821 obs. of  8 variables:
##  $ ID          : chr  &amp;quot;1&amp;quot; &amp;quot;2&amp;quot; &amp;quot;3&amp;quot; &amp;quot;4&amp;quot; ...
##  $ Timecode.in : chr  &amp;quot;00:00:02.445&amp;quot; &amp;quot;00:00:03.950&amp;quot; &amp;quot;00:00:05.890&amp;quot; &amp;quot;00:00:07.420&amp;quot; ...
##  $ Timecode.out: chr  &amp;quot;00:00:03.850&amp;quot; &amp;quot;00:00:05.765&amp;quot; &amp;quot;00:00:07.295&amp;quot; &amp;quot;00:00:08.925&amp;quot; ...
##  $ Text        : chr  &amp;quot;Morty, you got to... come on.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;- You got to come with me. - Rick, what&amp;#39;s going on?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I got a surprise for you, Morty.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s the middle of the night. What are you talking about?&amp;quot; ...
##  $ season      : chr  &amp;quot;Season_1&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Season_1&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Season_1&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Season_1&amp;quot; ...
##  $ season_num  : num  1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 ...
##  $ episode_num : num  1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 ...
##  $ serie       : chr  &amp;quot;rick and morty&amp;quot; &amp;quot;rick and morty&amp;quot; &amp;quot;rick and morty&amp;quot; &amp;quot;rick and morty&amp;quot; ...&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;$Text&lt;/code&gt; column contains the subtitle text, surrounded by additional variables for line id, timestamp, season and episode number. This is the structure preferred by the tidytext package, as it is by the rest of tidyverse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;morty-you-got-tocome-on.&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Morty, you got to…come on.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the bread and butter of text mining, &lt;em&gt;term frequencies&lt;/em&gt;. We split the text by word, exclude stop words,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;data(stop_words)
tidy_df &amp;lt;- df %&amp;gt;%
  unnest_tokens(word, Text) %&amp;gt;%
  anti_join(stop_words)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and aggregate and plot the top 10 words per season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(dplyr)
library(ggplot2)

tidy_df %&amp;gt;% group_by(season) %&amp;gt;%
        count(word, sort = TRUE) %&amp;gt;%
        top_n(10) %&amp;gt;%
        ggplot(aes(reorder(word,n), n, fill = season)) +
        geom_col() +
        coord_flip() +
        facet_wrap(~season, scales = &amp;quot;free_y&amp;quot;) +
        labs(x = NULL) +
        guides(fill = FALSE) +
        scale_fill_brewer(palette = &amp;quot;Set1&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mtoto/mtoto.github.io/master/blog/2017/2017-10-07-tidyrick_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-6-1.png&#34; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both seasons are dominated by, well, Rick and Morty. The main characters are tirelessly addressing each other, talking one another either into or out of the mess they find themselves in. What stands out most is the absence of Rick’s daughter, Beth from the top 10 in all seasons. She’s perhaps the only sane person of the family, but then again, sanity doesn’t get too much airtime on this show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;network-analysis-on-bi-grams&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Network analysis on bi-grams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can similarly get the number of times each &lt;em&gt;two words&lt;/em&gt; appear, called &lt;em&gt;bi-grams&lt;/em&gt;. Besides calculating summary statistics on bi-grams, we can now construct a network of words according to co-occurrence using &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/igraph/index.html&#34;&gt;igraph&lt;/a&gt;, the go-to package for network analysis in R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(tidyr)
library(igraph)

bigram_graph &amp;lt;- df %&amp;gt;%
  unnest_tokens(bigram, Text, token = &amp;quot;ngrams&amp;quot;, n = 2) %&amp;gt;%
  separate(bigram, c(&amp;quot;word1&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;word2&amp;quot;), sep = &amp;quot; &amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
  filter(!word1 %in% stop_words$word) %&amp;gt;%
  filter(!word2 %in% stop_words$word) %&amp;gt;% 
  group_by(season) %&amp;gt;%
  count(word1, word2, sort = TRUE) %&amp;gt;%
  select(word1, word2, season, n) %&amp;gt;%
  filter(n &amp;gt; 2) %&amp;gt;%
  graph_from_data_frame()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## Warning in graph_from_data_frame(.): In `d&amp;#39; `NA&amp;#39; elements were replaced
## with string &amp;quot;NA&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;print(bigram_graph)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## IGRAPH ec21a3c DN-- 311 283 -- 
## + attr: name (v/c), season (e/c), n (e/n)
## + edges from ec21a3c (vertex names):
## [1] NA      -&amp;gt;NA      NA      -&amp;gt;NA      NA      -&amp;gt;NA      tiny    -&amp;gt;rick   
## [5] yeah    -&amp;gt;yeah   
##  [ reached getOption(&amp;quot;max.print&amp;quot;) -- omitted 21 entries ]
## + ... omitted several edges&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This igraph object contains a directed network, where the vertices are the words and an edge exists between each that appear after one another more than twice. Representing the text as a graph, we can calculate things such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Centrality#Degree_centrality&#34;&gt;degree centrality&lt;/a&gt;, and plot the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mtoto/mtoto.github.io/master/blog/2017/2017-10-07-tidyrick_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-9-1.png&#34; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the largest connected network, we arrive at the same conclusion as with term frequencies. Rick and Morty are the most important words. They are at the center of the network and so have the highest degree centrality scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides visualising the importance of words in our network, we can similarly differentiate between words that precede either Rick or Morty. These are all the 1st degree connections (words) that have an edge pointing towards the main characters, but aren’t shared among the them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mtoto/mtoto.github.io/master/blog/2017/2017-10-07-tidyrick_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-10-1.png&#34; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the red nodes, we recognize many of the things Rick throws at Morty: &lt;em&gt;“Relax Morty!…It’s science Morty!…Run Morty!”&lt;/em&gt;. There is also a handful of words that precede both characters like &lt;em&gt;“Geez”, “Boy”&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;“God”&lt;/em&gt;. All other words that are more than one degree away, are colored blue as out of range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;tf-idf&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;tf-idf&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus far we have looked at all words across seasons. But where do the seasons differ from each other? And can we summarise each season using a handful of topics? To answer the first question, text mining’s most notorious statistic &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tf%E2%80%93idf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tf-idf&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; comes to the rescue. It stands for &lt;strong&gt;term frequency - inverse document frequency&lt;/strong&gt;. We take the word counts per season and multiply it by the &lt;em&gt;scaled inverse fraction of seasons that contain the word&lt;/em&gt;. Simply put, we penalize words that are common across all seasons, and reward ones that are not. This way, we bring forth the words most typical of each season. Again the tidytext implementation is super easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;tf_idf_df &amp;lt;- tidy_df %&amp;gt;% 
        count(season, word, sort = TRUE) %&amp;gt;%
        bind_tf_idf(word, season, n)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mtoto/mtoto.github.io/master/blog/2017/2017-10-07-tidyrick_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-12-1.png&#34; /&gt; What we get back are the most important elements, characters, motives or places across episodes. I’m somewhat surprised that Mr. Meeseeks didn’t come in first though. I was sure as hell annoyed out of my mind after hearing it uttered for the 100th time during the episode &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meeseeks_and_Destroy&#34;&gt;Meeseeks and Destroy&lt;/a&gt;. But then again, Mr Meeseeks does make a cameo in two other seasons, so that kind of torpedoes his chances for the first spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;topic-models&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Topic models&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having seen the most unique words of the script by seasons, we will take our analysis one last step further and try to capture the gist of a the show using topic modeling. Broadly speaking, it’s an unsupervised classification method that tries to represent a document as a collection of topics. Here, I will take the classic &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Latent_Dirichlet_allocation&#34;&gt;Latent Dirichlet Allocation or shortly LDA&lt;/a&gt; algorithm for a spin. The basic idea is that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“…a topic is defined as a mixture over words where each word has a probability of belonging to a topic. And a document is a mixture over topics, meaning that a single document can be composed of multiple topics.”&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could for example take season two, and tell &lt;code&gt;LDA()&lt;/code&gt; that we want to compress 10 episodes into just 6 topics. To compensate for the omnipresence of the top words across episodes, I will exclude them for the purpose of clearer separation of topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(topicmodels)
popular_words &amp;lt;- c(&amp;quot;rick&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;morty&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;yeah&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;hey&amp;quot;,
                   &amp;quot;summer&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;jerry&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;uh&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;gonna&amp;quot;)

episodes_dtm &amp;lt;- tidy_df %&amp;gt;% filter(season_num == 2 &amp;amp; !word %in% popular_words) %&amp;gt;%
        group_by(episode_num) %&amp;gt;%
        count(word, sort = TRUE) %&amp;gt;%
        cast_dtm(episode_num, word, n) 

episodes_lda &amp;lt;- LDA(episodes_dtm, k = 6, control = list(seed = 1234))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After &lt;code&gt;tidy()&lt;/code&gt;ing the results, we can plot the top 10 words that contribute (&lt;em&gt;beta&lt;/em&gt;) to most to each topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mtoto/mtoto.github.io/master/blog/2017/2017-10-07-tidyrick_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-14-1.png&#34; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s definitely a few topics that contain multiple elements of a particular episode. Take for example &lt;strong&gt;topic 1&lt;/strong&gt;. It includes “&lt;em&gt;Roy&lt;/em&gt;”, the name of the videogame Morty plays in the same episode “&lt;em&gt;Fart&lt;/em&gt;” appears, a gaseous creature kept under locks by aliens. Or &lt;strong&gt;topic 5&lt;/strong&gt;, which probably relates to the episode where Rick visits his old lover “&lt;em&gt;Unity&lt;/em&gt;”. It further contains words as “&lt;em&gt;remember&lt;/em&gt;” and “&lt;em&gt;memories&lt;/em&gt;”. The episode ends with Unity repeating “I want it &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only can we examine the &lt;strong&gt;word per topic probabilities&lt;/strong&gt;, we can also plot &lt;strong&gt;the topic per document probabilities&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;gamma&lt;/em&gt; values. This lets us see what topic belongs to what episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;tidy(episodes_lda, matrix = &amp;quot;gamma&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
        inner_join(titles) %&amp;gt;%
        ggplot(aes(factor(topic), gamma)) +
        geom_boxplot() +
        facet_wrap(~ title) +
        ggtitle(&amp;quot;Dominant Topics per Episode&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mtoto/mtoto.github.io/master/blog/2017/2017-10-07-tidyrick_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-16-1.png&#34; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our previous assumptions are confirmed, the first topic does belong to the episode &lt;em&gt;Mortynight Run&lt;/em&gt; as does the fifth topic to &lt;em&gt;Auto-Erotic Assimilation&lt;/em&gt;. It is important to note that the results strongly depend on the number of topics supplied to &lt;code&gt;LDA()&lt;/code&gt;, so inevitably, some experimentation is required to arrive at meaningful results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran through some very interesting concepts fairly quickly in this post. I owe much of it to the tidytext package. With very little coding, we can mine a tremendous amount of insights from textual data. And I have just scrachted the surface of what’s possible. The seamless integration with the tidyverse, as with igraph and topicmodels does make a huge difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, text mining is a complex topic and when arriving at more advanced material, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trinker/topicmodels_learning&#34;&gt;further reading&lt;/a&gt; on the inner workings of these algorithms might come in handy for effective use. The full &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mtoto/mtoto.github.io/tree/master/data/2017-10-07-tidyrick/rick%20and%20morty&#34;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mtoto/mtoto.github.io/blob/master/blog/2017/2017-10-07-tidyrick.Rmd&#34;&gt;code&lt;/a&gt; for this post is available as usual on my Github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-learning Hue Lights</title>
      <link>/blog/self-learning-hue-lights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 23:15:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/self-learning-hue-lights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
pre code, pre, code {
  white-space: pre !important;
  overflow-x: scroll !important;
  word-break: keep-all !important;
  word-wrap: initial !important;
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;the-rise-of-the-api&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The rise of the API&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rich API interfaces are one of the main ingredients of today’s smart devices. They are by definition built for interconnectivity and there is an active community of developers creating apps as microservices on top of them. Philips Hue is no exception with it’s wide variety of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.developers.meethue.com/otherapps/otherAppsIOS.html#appsList&#34;&gt;apps&lt;/a&gt; available to users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you don’t need to code an entire mobile application to take advantage of the low level access. Using modern tools it only takes a few lines of code to build a self-learning algorithm, running in production in your home. Not only can we access external API’s, we can just as easily expose static files, functions or models as an API of our own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My original inspiration for this post was &lt;a href=&#34;https://sc5.io/posts/autonomous-indoor-lighting-using-neural-networks/&#34;&gt;Max Pagel’s article&lt;/a&gt; on training a neural network to automatically control his Philips Hue lights. In fact, I purchased my first set of Hue bulbs because of it. In summary, this post will describe how to build and productionize a classifier in &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; that controls the brightness of Philips Hue lights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;stop-dinnertime&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Stop, dinnertime!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much like in my &lt;a href=&#34;http://tamaszilagyi.com/blog/creating-a-spotify-playlist-using-luigi/&#34;&gt;post on Spotify&lt;/a&gt; I have set up a cronjob to execute the Python script that pings the API and saves the lights’ state data locally, to be picked up by Luigi tasks for parsing and copying to S3 further downstream. You can find the relevant code on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mtoto/hue/blob/master/tasks.py&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.developers.meethue.com/philips-hue-api&#34;&gt;Hue API documentation&lt;/a&gt; contains information on authentication and the types of calls available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The starting point for this post will be the parsed &lt;code&gt;.json&lt;/code&gt; file containing all of the log data for my “Dinner Lamps”. They are the two main lights in my living and dining area room at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(aws.s3)
library(jsonlite)
# read file from amazon
aws.signature::use_credentials()
df &amp;lt;- s3read_using(object = paste0(&amp;quot;hue_full_2017-08-26.json&amp;quot;), fromJSON, bucket = &amp;quot;ams-hue-data&amp;quot;)
str(df)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## &amp;#39;data.frame&amp;#39;:    30322 obs. of  15 variables:
##  $ on.1       : logi  FALSE FALSE FALSE FALSE FALSE FALSE ...
##  $ on.2       : logi  FALSE FALSE FALSE FALSE FALSE FALSE ...
##  $ bri.2      : int  131 131 131 131 131 131 131 131 131 131 ...
##  $ type.1     : chr  &amp;quot;Dimmable light&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Dimmable light&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Dimmable light&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Dimmable light&amp;quot; ...
##  $ type.2     : chr  &amp;quot;Dimmable light&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Dimmable light&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Dimmable light&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Dimmable light&amp;quot; ...
##  $ bri.1      : int  131 131 131 131 131 131 131 131 131 131 ...
##  $ modelid.2  : chr  &amp;quot;LWB010&amp;quot; &amp;quot;LWB010&amp;quot; &amp;quot;LWB010&amp;quot; &amp;quot;LWB010&amp;quot; ...
##  $ modelid.1  : chr  &amp;quot;LWB010&amp;quot; &amp;quot;LWB010&amp;quot; &amp;quot;LWB010&amp;quot; &amp;quot;LWB010&amp;quot; ...
##  $ name.1     : chr  &amp;quot;Dinner Lamp 2&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Dinner Lamp 2&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Dinner Lamp 2&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Dinner Lamp 2&amp;quot; ...
##  $ reachable.1: logi  TRUE TRUE TRUE TRUE TRUE TRUE ...
##  $ reachable.2: logi  TRUE TRUE TRUE TRUE TRUE TRUE ...
##  $ name.2     : chr  &amp;quot;Dinner Lamp 1&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Dinner Lamp 1&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Dinner Lamp 1&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Dinner Lamp 1&amp;quot; ...
##  $ alert.1    : chr  &amp;quot;none&amp;quot; &amp;quot;none&amp;quot; &amp;quot;none&amp;quot; &amp;quot;none&amp;quot; ...
##  $ log_time   : chr  &amp;quot;2017-05-12 17:00:02&amp;quot; &amp;quot;2017-05-12 17:05:01&amp;quot; &amp;quot;2017-05-12 17:10:02&amp;quot; &amp;quot;2017-05-12 17:15:01&amp;quot; ...
##  $ alert.2    : chr  &amp;quot;none&amp;quot; &amp;quot;none&amp;quot; &amp;quot;none&amp;quot; &amp;quot;none&amp;quot; ...&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The structure of the original &lt;code&gt;.json&lt;/code&gt; file is such that each lamp has a separate (numbered) column for every variable. The dataset is essentially a timeseries where each row represent a snapshot of the lamps’ state at &lt;code&gt;$log_time&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;every 5 minutes&lt;/strong&gt;. Before moving on, let’s tidy things up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(tidyr)
tidy_df &amp;lt;- df %&amp;gt;% gather(key, value, -log_time) %&amp;gt;%
        separate(key, into = c(&amp;quot;variable&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;lamp&amp;quot;), sep = &amp;quot;\\.&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
        spread(variable, value)
str(tidy_df)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## &amp;#39;data.frame&amp;#39;:    60644 obs. of  9 variables:
##  $ log_time : chr  &amp;quot;2017-05-12 17:00:02&amp;quot; &amp;quot;2017-05-12 17:00:02&amp;quot; &amp;quot;2017-05-12 17:05:01&amp;quot; &amp;quot;2017-05-12 17:05:01&amp;quot; ...
##  $ lamp     : chr  &amp;quot;1&amp;quot; &amp;quot;2&amp;quot; &amp;quot;1&amp;quot; &amp;quot;2&amp;quot; ...
##  $ alert    : chr  &amp;quot;none&amp;quot; &amp;quot;none&amp;quot; &amp;quot;none&amp;quot; &amp;quot;none&amp;quot; ...
##  $ bri      : chr  &amp;quot;131&amp;quot; &amp;quot;131&amp;quot; &amp;quot;131&amp;quot; &amp;quot;131&amp;quot; ...
##  $ modelid  : chr  &amp;quot;LWB010&amp;quot; &amp;quot;LWB010&amp;quot; &amp;quot;LWB010&amp;quot; &amp;quot;LWB010&amp;quot; ...
##  $ name     : chr  &amp;quot;Dinner Lamp 2&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Dinner Lamp 1&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Dinner Lamp 2&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Dinner Lamp 1&amp;quot; ...
##  $ on       : chr  &amp;quot;FALSE&amp;quot; &amp;quot;FALSE&amp;quot; &amp;quot;FALSE&amp;quot; &amp;quot;FALSE&amp;quot; ...
##  $ reachable: chr  &amp;quot;TRUE&amp;quot; &amp;quot;TRUE&amp;quot; &amp;quot;TRUE&amp;quot; &amp;quot;TRUE&amp;quot; ...
##  $ type     : chr  &amp;quot;Dimmable light&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Dimmable light&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Dimmable light&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Dimmable light&amp;quot; ...&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 15 columns are now reduced to 9 because each variable appears only once thanks to adding the key column &lt;code&gt;$lamp&lt;/code&gt; to the dataset. But we are not quite done cleaning yet: I use the two lamps in sync, so we need only data from one of them. When the lamps are not &lt;code&gt;on&lt;/code&gt; nor &lt;code&gt;reachable&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;$bri&lt;/code&gt; should be set to &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt;. Using the now correct brightness values, we create the four categories for the classifier to work with. Lastly, there were days I wasn’t home, so we can rid of of those observations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(dplyr)
binned_df &amp;lt;- tidy_df %&amp;gt;% filter(lamp == &amp;quot;1&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
        mutate(bri = as.numeric(replace(bri, on==&amp;quot;FALSE&amp;quot; | reachable==&amp;quot;FALSE&amp;quot;,0)),
               y = as.factor(ifelse(bri == 0, &amp;quot;zero&amp;quot;,
                                    ifelse(between(bri,0,80), &amp;quot;dim&amp;quot;,
                                           ifelse(between(bri,80,160),&amp;quot;mid&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;bright&amp;quot;)))))

off_days &amp;lt;- binned_df %&amp;gt;% group_by(date = as.Date(log_time,tz=&amp;quot;Europe/Amsterdam&amp;quot;)) %&amp;gt;%
                dplyr::summarise(total_bri = sum(bri)) %&amp;gt;%
                filter(total_bri == 0 ) %&amp;gt;%
                select(date)

binned_df &amp;lt;- binned_df %&amp;gt;% filter(!as.Date(log_time) %in% off_days$date)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does the distribution of our target variable look?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;table(binned_df$y)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## 
## bright    dim    mid   zero 
##    598   1533   1710  23889&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roughly 86% of the time the lamps are off, resulting in an unbalanced dataset. What about brightness values lamps were &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt;, according to the three remaining categories?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../blog/2017/2017-05-14-hue_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-6-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distribution seems to be close to normal with a positive skew, and a massive outlier all the way at the end of the spectrum. That’s maximum brightness, the default when I switch the lights on/off with a physical switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get an intuition for my usage patterns, I’ll also plot a histogram of hour of the day for all four categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../blog/2017/2017-05-14-hue_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-7-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only times the lamps are &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; structurally off, is in the evening and the early hours. Dim and mid values are the dominant category after 8PM instead. Another slight dip in zero appears around and shortly after midnight, compensated by the second largest peak in dim, and a few instances of mid and bright. Bright observations in general are sparse and will be tough to predict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;can-we-learn-this&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Can we learn this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only variables I will use for training, are time based: &lt;em&gt;day of the week&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;month&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;week number&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;weekend or not&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;time of the day&lt;/em&gt;; and &lt;em&gt;minutes since 12PM, 6AM, 12AM and 6PM&lt;/em&gt;. A datetime string will then suffice to generate a prediction on the fly, a boon for putting things into production later on. I packaged a chain of dplyr commands inside the function &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mtoto/hue/blob/master/functions.R&#34;&gt;add_vars()&lt;/a&gt; to add the above variables to the dataset:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;df_vars &amp;lt;- binned_df %&amp;gt;% add_vars(extra_var = &amp;quot;yes&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember we are dealing with an unbalanced dataset, that also happens to be a timeseries. To remedy the former, I will use class weights to penalize the misclassification of the minority classes. Secondly, I will look at the &lt;em&gt;Area Under the Curve&lt;/em&gt; to evaluate the model, which will be less affected than &lt;em&gt;Accuracy&lt;/em&gt; by class imbalance if I set dim as the positive class. If not for these measures, the algorithm would gladly classify 100% of instances as &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;zero&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;, achieving stunning accuracy on paper and complete darkness in my living room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, why does it matter that we have a timeseries? In any dataset with a time component, the split between train and test sets should not be random. Otherwise, the model can and will &lt;strong&gt;learn from the future&lt;/strong&gt;, and severely overfit the data. The correct cross-validation strategy instead is to fold the data according to time. Train should always the before and test the after. For our convenience &lt;code&gt;caret&lt;/code&gt; provides the &lt;code&gt;createTimeSlices()&lt;/code&gt; function to create the indices of the CV-folds. An extra &lt;code&gt;testing&lt;/code&gt; set will be held out to validate our model on unseen data after we are done modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll now train a &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/gbm/index.html&#34;&gt;gbm&lt;/a&gt; model, using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://topepo.github.io/caret/&#34;&gt;caret&lt;/a&gt; package, which comes with a myriad of convenience tools to make the process easier and the code a lot more concise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(caret)
# Split train and test sets
training &amp;lt;- df_vars[df_vars$date &amp;lt; &amp;quot;2017-08-05&amp;quot;,] %&amp;gt;% select(-date,-log_time)
testing &amp;lt;- df_vars[df_vars$date &amp;gt;= &amp;quot;2017-08-05&amp;quot;,] %&amp;gt;% select(-date)

# create cross validation folds
idx &amp;lt;- createTimeSlices(1:nrow(training), 
                      initialWindow = 15000, 
                      horizon = 5000, skip = 1000, fixedWindow = F)

# create model weights vector
model_weights &amp;lt;- ifelse(training$y == &amp;quot;zero&amp;quot;,0.2,
                        ifelse(training$y == &amp;quot;mid&amp;quot;,1.2,1))

# define cross validation logic
fitControl &amp;lt;- trainControl(## 10-fold CV
        index = idx[[1]],
        indexOut = idx[[2]],
        summaryFunction = multiClassSummary,
        classProbs = T)

# create tunegrid for hyperparameter search
gbmGrid &amp;lt;-  expand.grid(interaction.depth = c(1,3,5), 
                        n.trees = c(5,10,30), 
                        shrinkage = c(0.1),
                        n.minobsinnode = 5)

# train model
gbmFit &amp;lt;- train(y ~ ., data = training, 
                method = &amp;quot;gbm&amp;quot;, 
                trControl = fitControl,
                metric = &amp;quot;AUC&amp;quot;,
                weights = model_weights,
                verbose = FALSE,
                tuneGrid = gbmGrid)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Printing &lt;code&gt;gbmFit&lt;/code&gt; to the console will give us the performance metrics across hyperparameters, and the ultimately selected values maximizing our metric of choice. While this is certainly useful information, I find it more intuitive to immediately look at the confusion matrix and see where our model is going off the rails:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;preds&amp;lt;-predict(gbmFit, testing)
table(preds, testing$y)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;##         
## preds     dim  mid bright zero
##   dim     105  205     31  366
##   mid      58  102      6   61
##   bright   14   34      0    3
##   zero     43  102     28 4314&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most mistakes are made trying to classify bright and mid. The model gets 0 bright values right and only manages to do so correctly 14% of the time for mid. But when do errors happen? To dig a little deeper let’s look at the previous histogram of categories by hour again for the test set, but now with the predictions overlaid on top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../blog/2017/2017-05-14-hue_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-11-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bright values were always going be hard to guess, but the model at least comes close in terms of hours, but off on the exact days. The majority of misclassification comes from overzealously predicting dim in the evening and around midnight, when it should really be either mid or zero. That looks like a workable scenario for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;lets-ship-it&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Let’s ship it!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To control the lights, we can make PUT requests to the Hue bridge. To set &lt;em&gt;bri&lt;/em&gt;, we need actual brightness values. An intuitive option is to pick the median values per category per hour:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;median_values &amp;lt;- binned_df %&amp;gt;% filter(bri &amp;gt; 0) %&amp;gt;% 
                mutate(hour = lubridate::hour(as.POSIXct(log_time, tz = &amp;quot;Europe/Amsterdam&amp;quot;))) %&amp;gt;%
                select(hour,bri, y) %&amp;gt;% 
                group_by(y, hour) %&amp;gt;%
                dplyr::summarise(med = median(bri)) %&amp;gt;%
                ungroup()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because we only used date and time based features for modeling, all we need for a prediction is a timestamp string. Using &lt;code&gt;for_sample&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;def_vars()&lt;/code&gt;, we define a custom function &lt;code&gt;predict_hue()&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;predict_hue &amp;lt;- function(timestamp){
        
        df &amp;lt;- data.frame(log_time =as.POSIXct(timestamp)) %&amp;gt;% 
                add_vars(extra_var = &amp;quot;no&amp;quot;)
        
        pred &amp;lt;- predict(gbmFit, newdata = df)
        
        if (pred==&amp;quot;zero&amp;quot;) {
                x &amp;lt;- 0
        } else {
                x &amp;lt;- median_values %&amp;gt;% filter(y == pred &amp;amp; hour == lubridate::hour(timestamp)) %&amp;gt;%
                select(med) %&amp;gt;% unlist()
        }
        
        return(x)
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to expose the above function as an API, we literally need three lines of code with &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/jug/vignettes/jug.html&#34;&gt;jug&lt;/a&gt;. Ever since I saw the package &lt;a href=&#34;https://channel9.msdn.com/Events/useR-international-R-User-conferences/useR-International-R-User-2017-Conference/jug-Building-Web-APIs-for-R&#34;&gt;presented at useR2017&lt;/a&gt;, I have been looking for a use case to play with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(jug)
jug() %&amp;gt;% post(&amp;quot;/predict-hue&amp;quot;, decorate(predict_hue)) %&amp;gt;%
        simple_error_handler_json() %&amp;gt;%
        serve_it()
#Serving the jug at http://127.0.0.1:8080&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great. We can now make calls to this API and get a prediction supplying the current time. The nifty thing is that because API’s are language agnostic, we can access it from the programming paradigm of our choosing. I currently have a basic Python function that communicates with both API’s, transferring a prediction to the Hue Bridge every 5 minutes. But we could just as well build a whole interface on top, or create a chatbot for improved user experience. Perhaps I’ll do a follow-up post on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;conclusion&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is something very satisfying about building your own data products and seeing them at work. Even something as trivial as controlling the light switch for you. I only have data since this year May, so there’s a good chance our model will get smarter as days go by. We can easily schedule to retrain the model every week or even day, without having to lift a finger. Most of the code in this post is packaged up as a handful of &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; functions deployed on my Raspberry Pi. Now, when I &lt;em&gt;choose&lt;/em&gt; to pass out on my couch next time, at least lights won’t stay on for too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Spotify Playlist using Luigi</title>
      <link>/blog/creating-a-spotify-playlist-using-luigi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/creating-a-spotify-playlist-using-luigi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
pre code, pre, code {
  white-space: pre !important;
  overflow-x: scroll !important;
  word-break: keep-all !important;
  word-wrap: initial !important;
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;introduction&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;http://tamaszilagyi.com/blog/analyzing-my-spotify-listening-history/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I shared an analysis of my Spotify listening history using R. In this post, I will discuss what came before having the data: collecting, cleaning and saving it. As the title suggest, we will even go a step further and automate the creation of a weekly top 10 playlist in Spotify using the very same dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main ingredient will be Luigi, a Python framework for workflow management Spotify open-sourced a couple of years ago. According to &lt;a href=&#34;http://luigi.readthedocs.io/en/stable/index.html&#34;&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of Luigi is to address all the plumbing typically associated with long-running batch processes. You want to chain many tasks, automate them, and failures will happen. These tasks can be anything, but are typically long running things like Hadoop jobs, dumping data to/from databases, running machine learning algorithms, or anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designed for massive jobs, implementing Luigi on top of tiny little &lt;code&gt;.json&lt;/code&gt; files might seem like a huge overkill, but the logic we will define won’t considerably differ from larger scale applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;the-pipeline&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The pipeline&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can break down the pipeline into four tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://tamaszilagyi.com/img/luigi2.png&#34; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;cronjob-to-ping-the-api&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Cronjob to ping the API&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial step is to ping the API, and store the raw response as a &lt;code&gt;.json&lt;/code&gt; file locally. We need to have the &lt;code&gt;client_id&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;client_secret&lt;/code&gt; and a &lt;code&gt;refresh_token&lt;/code&gt; to generate a temporary access token. Follow the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.spotify.com/web-api/tutorial/&#34;&gt;Web API tutorial by Spotify&lt;/a&gt; to attain them. In turn, the access token is required to make calls to the API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We start with two functions: One to generate the &lt;code&gt;access_token&lt;/code&gt; using our credentials (I have them inside &lt;code&gt;spotify_creds&lt;/code&gt;), and a second one to download our listening history, dumping the data in a new &lt;code&gt;.json&lt;/code&gt; file every day. To make sure that the access token doesn’t expire, we’ll generate a new one with every call to the API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will store functions inside &lt;code&gt;functions.py&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;import requests
import json
import datetime
from spotify_creds import *
# Get access token
def access_token():
    
    body_params = {&amp;#39;grant_type&amp;#39; : &amp;#39;refresh_token&amp;#39;,
                &amp;#39;refresh_token&amp;#39; : refresh_token}
    url = &amp;#39;https://accounts.spotify.com/api/token&amp;#39;
    response = requests.post(url, 
                             data = body_params, 
                             auth = (client_id, client_secret))
    
    response_dict = json.loads(response.content)
    accessToken = response_dict.get(&amp;#39;access_token&amp;#39;)
    return accessToken
    
# Get most recent songs and append the response
# to a new json file every day
def download_data():
    current_time = datetime.datetime.now().strftime(&amp;#39;%Y-%m-%d&amp;#39;)
    filename = &amp;#39;/spotify/json/spotify_tracks_%s.json&amp;#39; % current_time
    
    accesToken = access_token()
    headers = {&amp;#39;Authorization&amp;#39;: &amp;#39;Bearer &amp;#39; + accesToken }
    payload = {&amp;#39;limit&amp;#39;: 50}
    url = &amp;#39;https://api.spotify.com/v1/me/player/recently-played&amp;#39;
    response = requests.get(url, headers = headers,
                            params = payload)
    data = response.json()
    with open(filename, &amp;#39;a&amp;#39;) as f:
        json.dump(data[&amp;#39;items&amp;#39;], f)
        f.write(&amp;#39;\n&amp;#39;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, to make sure that I don’t miss any songs I have listened to, I will set up a cronjob to execute &lt;code&gt;download_data()&lt;/code&gt; (that’s what &lt;code&gt;logger.py&lt;/code&gt; contains) every three hours. We first make this file executable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;chmod +x /spotify/logger.py&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;open crontab,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;crontab -e&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and add the following line to our list of cronjobs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;0 */3 * * * /usr/bin/python /spotify/logger.py&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The part with the numbers and &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt;’s gives the scheduling logic. The second bit is the Python environment from which to call the script. If you prefer self-contained environments instead, then this will look something like &lt;code&gt;/home/pi/miniconda/envs/name_of_env/bin/python&lt;/code&gt; on a Raspberry Pi using &lt;a href=&#34;https://conda.io/miniconda.html&#34;&gt;miniconda&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;deduplicate-and-save-to-s3&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Deduplicate and save to S3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With raw data coming in, the next step is to store the result somewhere more robust than the SD card inside my Pi. Because we are pinging the API every three hours, we have files that contain 8 dictionaries of the last 50 tracks. Unless I listen to Spotify non-stop all day every day, there is going to be lots of redundancy because of duplicate records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function &lt;code&gt;deduplicate()&lt;/code&gt; takes &lt;code&gt;.json&lt;/code&gt; file we created above, and returns the deduplicated list of dictionaries containing only unique items according to the key &lt;code&gt;played_at&lt;/code&gt;, which is the timestamp of each song played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Cleaner function to get rid of redundancy
def deduplicate(file):
    result =[]
    
    for line in file:
        data = json.loads(line)
        result.extend(data)
    
    result = {i[&amp;#39;played_at&amp;#39;]:i for i in result}.values()
    return result&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this point onwards, we are going to switch to using &lt;strong&gt;Luigi&lt;/strong&gt;. The main building block is a Task, which &lt;em&gt;usually&lt;/em&gt; consists of three methods:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;requires()&lt;/code&gt;: What other task the current one depends on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;run()&lt;/code&gt;: What is our tasks going to do, usually some function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;output()&lt;/code&gt;: Where will the result be stored.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In turn, &lt;code&gt;output()&lt;/code&gt; will end up in the &lt;code&gt;require()&lt;/code&gt; method of a consecutive task. This builds a dependency graph between tasks. Let’s jump right in, and look at how we apply this logic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;import luigi
from datetime import date, timedelta
from functions import *
# External task at the bottom of our dependancy graph,
# only looks to see if output of cronjob exists,
# by default from yesterday.
class local_raw_json(luigi.ExternalTask):
    date = luigi.DateParameter(default = date.today()-timedelta(1)) 
    def output(self):
        return luigi.LocalTarget(&amp;#39;spotify/json/spotify_tracks_%s.json&amp;#39; % 
                                 self.date.strftime(&amp;#39;%Y-%m-%d&amp;#39;))
        &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first task &lt;code&gt;local_raw_json&lt;/code&gt; is an &lt;strong&gt;External Task&lt;/strong&gt; with only an &lt;code&gt;output()&lt;/code&gt; method. This task does not run anything and does not depend on anything. It simply confirms the existence of a file, namely the output from our cronjob. Luigi allows for parameterization of tasks, so we define a &lt;code&gt;date&lt;/code&gt; parameter with the default value yesterday. We pass this to the &lt;code&gt;output()&lt;/code&gt; method to look for the file with the correct date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;External tasks with no dependencies are common first steps, especially if we are relying on an external datadump somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;import json
from luigi.s3 import S3Target, S3Client
# Task that runs our deduplicate() on local file 
# and writes the output to S3 bucket.
class spotify_clean_aws(luigi.Task):
    date = luigi.DateParameter(default = date.today()-timedelta(1)) 
    
    def requires(self):
        return self.clone(local_raw_json)
        
    def run(self):   
        with self.input().open(&amp;#39;r&amp;#39;) as in_file:
            data = deduplicate(in_file)
            
        with self.output().open(&amp;#39;w&amp;#39;) as out_file:
            json.dump(data, out_file)
    def output(self):
        client = S3Client(host = &amp;#39;s3.us-east-2.amazonaws.com&amp;#39;)
        return S3Target(&amp;#39;s3://myspotifydata/spotify_tracks_%s.json&amp;#39; % 
                        self.date.strftime(&amp;#39;%Y-%m-%d&amp;#39;), 
                        client=client)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second tasks is &lt;code&gt;spotify_clean_aws&lt;/code&gt;. This is where we run the &lt;code&gt;deduplicate()&lt;/code&gt; function defined earlier and write the output to an &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/s3/&#34;&gt;AWS S3&lt;/a&gt; bucket. In contrary to the first task, all three methods are present:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Require&lt;/strong&gt; that the raw json file exists, and also &lt;code&gt;clone()&lt;/code&gt; the parameters from the first task. This way the same date parameter will be passed to both tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Run&lt;/strong&gt; the function &lt;code&gt;deduplicate()&lt;/code&gt; on the input file and save the result as a .json.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Output&lt;/strong&gt; the result of the task to S3. Luigi has built-in support for AWS S3 that uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://boto3.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&#34;&gt;boto3&lt;/a&gt; under the hood. To connect, we need to have AWS credentials. They usually reside under &lt;code&gt;~/.aws/credentials&lt;/code&gt;, if you have run &lt;code&gt;aws configure&lt;/code&gt; in the Terminal before:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[default]
aws_access_key_id = YOUR_ACCESS_KEY
aws_secret_access_key = YOUR_SECRET_KEY &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also possible to pass them explicitly to &lt;code&gt;S3Client()&lt;/code&gt; however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;get-relevant-fields-and-create-weekly-dataset&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Get relevant fields and create weekly dataset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the data deduplicated and safely stored in the cloud, we can now parse the files, selecting a handful of fields from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.spotify.com/web-api/web-api-personalization-endpoints/get-recently-played/&#34;&gt;response&lt;/a&gt;. Because nobody ever gets excited about ETL code, I will omit the contents of &lt;code&gt;parse_json()&lt;/code&gt; here. It is suffice to say that we get a more compact result than what I used in the previous post. An example record from the resulting dictionary will look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{&amp;quot;played_at&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;2017-04-22T18:49:54.108Z&amp;quot;, 
 &amp;quot;track_name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Symphony No. 5 In C Minor Part 1&amp;quot;, 
 &amp;quot;duration_ms&amp;quot;: 485293, 
 &amp;quot;type&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;track&amp;quot;, 
 &amp;quot;artist_id&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;2wOqMjp9TyABvtHdOSOTUS&amp;quot;], 
 &amp;quot;explicit&amp;quot;: false, 
 &amp;quot;uri&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;spotify:track:0ZN01wuIdn4iT8VBggkOMm&amp;quot;, 
 &amp;quot;artist_name&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;Ludwig van Beethoven&amp;quot;], 
 &amp;quot;track_id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;0ZN01wuIdn4iT8VBggkOMm&amp;quot;}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can still find all the code for &lt;code&gt;parse_json()&lt;/code&gt; function (and all the others) on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mtoto/mtoto.github.io/tree/master/data/2017-07-22-spotifyLuigi&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, we’ll merge a week worth of data and store the intermediate result on S3. With these ingredients, we define our third Luigi Task: &lt;code&gt;spotify_merge_weekly_aws&lt;/code&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Task that merges the 7 daily datasets, 
# parses relevant fields, deduplicates records
# and stores the result in S3.
class spotify_merge_weekly_aws(luigi.Task):
    date = luigi.DateParameter(default = (date.today()-timedelta(8)))
    daterange = luigi.IntParameter(7)
    def requires(self):
        # take data from the 7 days following date param (8 days prior to current date by default)
        return [spotify_clean_aws(i) for i in [self.date + timedelta(x) for x in range(self.daterange)]]
     
    def run(self):
        results = []
        for file in self.input():
            
            with file.open(&amp;#39;r&amp;#39;) as in_file:
                data = json.load(in_file)
                parsed = parse_json(data)
                
            results.extend(parsed)
        # merging of daily data creates dupe records still
        result = {v[&amp;#39;played_at&amp;#39;]:v for v in results}.values()
        
        with self.output().open(&amp;#39;w&amp;#39;) as out_file:
            json.dump(result, out_file)
            
    def output(self):
        client = S3Client(host = &amp;#39;s3.us-east-2.amazonaws.com&amp;#39;)
        return S3Target(&amp;#39;s3://myspotifydata/spotify_week_%s.json&amp;#39; % 
                        (self.date.strftime(&amp;#39;%Y-%m-%d&amp;#39;) + &amp;#39;_&amp;#39; + str(self.daterange)), 
                         client=client)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;create-playlist&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. Create playlist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a last step, we aggregate the weekly data and fill up our playlist on Spotify. These are the last two functions we need to define. Not to complicate things too much, I am simply going to create a top 10 of &lt;em&gt;my most listened to tracks between 7am and 12pm&lt;/em&gt;. Sort of a morning playlist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# This function takes a list of track uri&amp;#39;s 
# to replace songs in my morning playlist
# and returns the status code of the put request.
def replace_tracks(tracks):
    
    url = &amp;#39;https://api.spotify.com/v1/users/1170891844/playlists/6a2QBfOgCqFQLN08FUxpj3/tracks&amp;#39;
    accesToken = access_token()
    headers = {&amp;#39;Authorization&amp;#39;: &amp;#39;Bearer &amp;#39; + accesToken,
               &amp;#39;Content-Type&amp;#39;:&amp;#39;application/json&amp;#39;}
    data = {&amp;quot;uris&amp;quot;: &amp;#39;,&amp;#39;.join(tracks)}
    response = requests.put(url, headers = headers,
                            params = data)
                            
    return response.status_code
                            
# This function reads in the weekly dataset 
# as a pandas dataframe, outputs the list of 
# top ten tracks and feeds them to replace_tracks()
def create_playlist(dataset, date):
    
    data = pd.read_json(dataset)          
    data[&amp;#39;played_at&amp;#39;] = pd.to_datetime(data[&amp;#39;played_at&amp;#39;])
    
    data = data.set_index(&amp;#39;played_at&amp;#39;) \
               .between_time(&amp;#39;7:00&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;12:00&amp;#39;)
        
    data = data[data.index &amp;gt; str(date)]
    # aggregate data
    songs = data[&amp;#39;uri&amp;#39;].value_counts()\
                       .nlargest(10) \
                       .index \
                       .get_values() \
                       .tolist()
    # make api call
    res_code = replace_tracks(songs)
    
    return res_code&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we wrap the above inside our last Luigi Task, &lt;code&gt;spotify_morning_playlist&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Task to aggregate weekly data and create playlist
class spotify_morning_playlist(luigi.Task):
    date = luigi.DateParameter(default = (date.today()-timedelta(8)))
    daterange = luigi.IntParameter(7)
    def requires(self):
        return self.clone(spotify_merge_weekly_aws)
    
    def run(self):
        
        with self.input().open(&amp;#39;r&amp;#39;) as in_file:
            res_code = create_playlist(in_file, self.date)      
        # write to file if succesful
        if (res_code == 201):
            with self.output().open(&amp;#39;w&amp;#39;) as out_file:
                json.dump(res_code, out_file)
    
    def output(self):
        client = S3Client(host = &amp;#39;s3.us-east-2.amazonaws.com&amp;#39;)
        return S3Target(&amp;#39;s3://myspotifydata/spotify_top10_%s.json&amp;#39; % 
                        (self.date.strftime(&amp;#39;%Y-%m-%d&amp;#39;) + &amp;#39;_&amp;#39; + str(self.daterange)), 
                        client=client)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have put all of the tasks in a file named &lt;code&gt;tasks.py&lt;/code&gt;. Luigi does not provide a scheduling mechanism out of the box, so we’ll trigger the tasks from crontab instead. For example every Monday at 7AM:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;0 7 * * 1 /usr/bin/python /spotify/tasks.py spotify_morning_playlist&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that we should have the &lt;a href=&#34;http://luigi.readthedocs.io/en/stable/central_scheduler.html&#34;&gt;Central Scheduler&lt;/a&gt; running in the background for the above to execute. The neat thing is that we only need to trigger the last task, and then Luigi considers all the dependencies and runs them if needed (ie. if the target file does not exists). Additionally, Luigi has a real nice GUI running on &lt;code&gt;localhost:8082&lt;/code&gt;, where we can visualise the complete dependency graph and monitor the progress of our tasks: &lt;img src=&#34;http://tamaszilagyi.com/img/dag.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If nothing fails, the tracks in the below playlist get updated every Monday morning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/user/1170891844/playlist/6a2QBfOgCqFQLN08FUxpj3&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have tried to give a simple, yet fully reproducible example of how to set up a workflow using Luigi. It is important to note that building data pipelines for production systems does require a little more effort. To name a few shortcomings of the above: We haven’t defined logging, we didn’t clean up our original files containing the raw response data, and it is very likely that the same tracks will end up in this playlist on consecutive weeks. Not something you would want to happen to your Discover Weekly for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about Luigi, I encourage you to read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://luigi.readthedocs.io/en/stable/index.html&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; and most of all start experimenting on personal projects. I find that is always the best way to learn new skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, we could also create playlists that are more useful to us than a simple top 10 playlist. What if we took artists we listen to the most, and automatically put their songs not in our listening history yet in a new playlist. It is perfectly possible, and probably more valuable to us as users. We just need to write a couple new functions, plug them into a similar Luigi pipeline as above and let it do the work for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>