- Cynthia...
- Oh, my God! No, no...
- I told you!
- Hold on...
Will you please...
Not marry me?
I choose Veronica.
- What?
- Yes!
- Called it.
- Why would he choose Veronica?
Because he loves her.
Well... if it's any
consolation, Summer,
none of it mattered, and
the entire show is stupid.
Okay, I've got an idea, Rick.
You show us your
concept of "good TV",
and we'll crap all over that.
I thought you'd never ask.
Hey!
Oh, cool! Is that
crystallized Zanthonite?
It conducts electrons
across dimensions.
Twenty percent accurate,
as usual, Morty.
The important thing
being I just upgraded
our cable package with programming
from every conceivable reality.
Wait, does that mean we get
Showtime Extreme?
How about Showtime Extreme in a
world where man evolved from corn.
We're not so different.
We're both corn of action.
Yeah. But one of us is...
dead corn!
- Boring.
- Summer,
you just spent three months,
watching a man choose a fake wife.
So what? It'd be better if
the people were corn?
Jerry, you don't get it.
This is infinite TV,
from infinite universes.
Look.
This shit is delicious.
A movie about a
guy eating shit.
A violent Antiques Show...
- It's a pleasure to have you.
- The pleasure's all mine.
Letterman from a
time line where Jerry's famous...
- Wait!
- What in the hell?
I agree.
Where is this going?
No, the other thing!
Go back!
Really?
All right, fine.
Glenn, this is a court order.
It says you can't eat shit anymore.
All right, Jerry, when you're right,
you're right. Now I'm hooked.
Rick and Morty S01E08
"Rixty Minutes"
Translated back from Portuguese
by paulo loppes
Corrections by TPBfan
Tweaking by XhmikosR
www.addic7ed.com
Coming up next on "Shmloo's the
Shmloss", Shmlony has a nightmare.
Shmlantha, Schmlona!
Amazing. A dimension where all
proper nouns begin with "Schmla".
Schmlove,
Schmlandula, Schmlonathan...
All right, that got... that
actually got old pretty quick.
Rick, would you please
go back to me on David Letterman?
Infinity's a big number, Jerry.
I don't remember the channel.
- Go back, go back!
- Jeez...
You speak da tru-tru.
Oh my God!
Dad's in Cloud Atlas!
I'm in Cloud Atlas!
What's Cloud Atlas?
Sometimes small tru-tru
different than da big tru-tru.
How is this possible?
Infinite time lines,
infinite possibilities.
Including a time line where
Jerry's a movie star.
Look, you guys are getting excited
about the wrong aspect of this device.
Wa... Look at this.
And now, another
Quick Mystery.
I just want to know who could've done
something like this. It's a travesty!
I did. See this knife and all the blood
on it? Here's my fingerprints.
Guilty! I sentence you
to life in prison.
- Here's another Quick Mystery.
- My mother's dead!
And I killed her.
Here's the weapon.
And cuff me, thank
you very much.
Guilty!
Sentenced to murder.
- Here's another.
- I'm the killer!
Wow, that one was really
quick, wasn't it?
Now who wants to watch random, crazy
TV shows from different dimensions...
and then who wants to narcissistically
obsess about their alternate self?
- I want to obsess about myself.
- The narcisstic stuff.
Here. These scan your retinas,
and let you view parallel time lines
through genetically matching
versions of your eyes.
Go fetch!
- Yes! This is so cool!
- Ladies First!
I'm proud of you, Morty.
Hey man, I don't give a
crap about myself, Rick.
Let's watch some
crazy stuff, yo!
I'm Ants-In-My-Eyes Johnson,
Here at Ants-in-My-Eyes
Johnson's Electronics.
I mean, there's so
many ants in my eyes!
And there's so many TVs,
microwaves, radios...
I think, I can't... I'm not 100%
sure what we have here in stock,
because I can't see anything.
Our prices I
hope aren't too low!
Check out this refrigerator!
Only $200!
What about this microwave?
Only $100! That's fair!
I'm Ants-in-My-Eyes Johnson!
Everything's black, I
can't see a thing!
And also I can't feel anything
either, did I mention that?
But that's not as catchy
as having ants in your eyes.
So that always goes, you know,
off by the wayside.
I can't feel.
It's a very rare disease.
All my... All my nerves, they don't
allow for the sensation of touch.
So I never know what's going on.
Am I standing? Sitting? I don't know.
Are we sure we want to do this?
Look at our own alternate lives?
You're right. Maybe we should
just play Yahtzee. Give me those!
- What do you see?
- Whiteness. Pure whiteness.
You're my best friend, Jerry Smith.
I love doing cocaine with you.
Whoa... I love doing cocaine
with you too, Johnny Depp!
Haven't we spent enough
time on you?
I'm performing surgery...
but not on a horse,
on a human!
That's great, Beth! You always wanted to
be a real surgeon.
I am a real surgeon.
- Ahh... uh... Summer's turn!
- Finally!
I don't see anything.
Well, you should select a
different timeline,
I mean, if your father and I
achieved our dreams,
there's a chance
you weren't even born.
That came out wrong.
That came out very wrong.
Fine, I'll find a world
where you bothered to have me.
We're playing Yahtzee.
- Yahtzee's fun. We love Yahtzee.
- It's a fun game for fun families!
Hey, could I get those
goggles back for a second?
It's a 45 horsepower
with anti-lock brakes,
and it's the official car of
Mr. Sneezy 3D.
It's the brand-new...
Sneezy XL.
The horn when you honk it
makes a sneeze noise.
It's polite, it's right,
and it's Sneezy...
Deezy... Mc... Deluxe.
Oh, I'm Mr. Sneezy!
Achoo!
Huh, seems like TV from other dimensions
has a somewhat looser feel to it.
Yeah, it's got an almost
improvisational tone.
It's in theaters now!
Coming this summer:
Two brothers. In a van.
And then a meteor hit.
And they ran as fast as they could...
from giant cat monsters.
And then a giant
tornado came...
and that's when things got
knocked into 12th gear.
A Mexican armada shows up.
With weapons made
from To-...tomatoes.
And you better bet
your bottom dollar...
that these two brothers know
how to handle business.
In: Alien Invasion Tomato
Monster Mexican Armada Brothers,
Who Are Just Regular Brothers, Running
In a van from an Asteroid...
and All Sorts of Things... THE MOVIE!
Hold on, there's more!
Old women are coming, and they're also
in the movie, and they're gonna come,
and cross... attack...
these two brothers.
But let's get back to
the brothers, because
they're... they
have a strong bond.
You don't want to know about it here,
but I'll tell you one thing: The moon...
...it comes crashing into Earth.
And what do you do then?
It's two brothers and...
and th-they're... It's called...
Two brothers... Two brothers!
It's just called Two Brothers.
Holy crap, I am
winning a Nobel Prize.
Come on!
Time's up!
I'm taming a lion!
No, wait, uh... there are film cameras.
I might be a lion-tamer in a movie.
You get the idea.
I work with lions.
Ooh, we're not playing Yahtzee,
we're playing Chutes and Ladders.
It seems like when I exist,
life gets a little more,
I don't know... predictable?
When two people
create a life together,
they set aside their
previous lives as individuals.
Gimme a break! We're not heroes for
having unprotected sex on prom night.
Oh, I get it. Now that you know
you could have had it better,
you resent me
for holding you back.
Now that we know you think
the tables are turning,
we know you thought
there were unturned tables!
- What are you talking about?
- All this time, you've been thinking,
"What if that loser Jerry hadn't
talked me out of the abortion?"
Well now you know,
you'd be a doctor.
Whoop-dee-doo.
You'd also be drinking wine, alone
in a house full of exotic birds.
And I'd be on DiCaprio's yacht,
banging Kristen Stewart!
You thought about
getting an abortion?
Everyone thinks about it.
Obviously, I'm the version
of me that didn't do it.
- So... you're welcome.
- Yeah, you're welcome.
Yeah, thank you guys so much. It's
a real treat to be raised by parents
that force themselves to be together
instead of being happy.
Hey, do we have any
wafer cookies?
Oh, boy. Looks like you guys have been
checking out alternate lives and realizing
you don't have it as good, huh?
That's too bad.
You know, me and Morty
are having a blast,
We just discovered a show
called "Ball Fondlers".
I mean, I don't want to rub
it in or anything,
but you guys clearly backed the
wrong conceptual horse.
- I'm in heaven right now.
- This might be the best day of my life.
So now what do we do?
That show "Ball Fondlers"
sounded kind of interesting.
- Dad!
- What?
They're having fun in there!
What do you guys want from me?
Every family on this block has to
wonder if they're together by choice.
Our family just has
inter-dimensional goggles
to show us for a
fact that we're not.
- We'll I'm leaving!
- You can't leave, you're 17!
Yeah, and I'm not pregnant.
I'm gonna have better judgment
than you guys had at my age.
I'm gonna... move to
the southwest and...
I don't know, do something
with turquoise.
It's Saturday Night Live!
Starring...
...a piece of toast!
Two guys, with handle-bar mustaches!
A man painted silver who
makes robot noises!
Gar Manarnar!
Three... uh... uh, uh, uh,
I'll get back to that one...
A hole in the wall, where
the men can see it all...
and returning, for his 25th
consecutive year: Bobby Moynihan!
Interesting fun fact, uh, Moynihan
and piece of toast hate each other.
Apparently they've got some real
creative differences.
Hey, are you tired of real doors,
cluttering up your house,
where you open 'em, and
they actually go somewhere?
And you go in another room?
Get on down to
"Real Fake Doors"!
That's us. Fill a whole
room up with 'em.
See? Watch, check this out!
Won't open. Won't open.
Not this one, not this one.
None of 'em open!
FakeDoors.com is our website,
so check it out for a lot of really
great deals on fake doooooooors!
Hey, wait a minute, Rick.
I thought this was a commercial.
- What's going on? I mean...
- Relax, Morty.
Don't worry about it... Let's just...
just see where this goes.
Step on it,
we all got places to be!
Son of a bitch!
See, that must be where
he lives... OK.
Huh. Making himself a
sandwich now...
Hey everybody!
So this is my house,
I just made a sandwich,
peanut butter and jelly,
still here,
still selling fake doors!
- What?
- Oh, my God! It's still the commercial!
We have fake doors...
like you wouldn't believe!
What are you worried about?
Come get fake doors.
Call us up, and order some
fake doors today.
Don't even hesitate,
Don't even worry and don't even...
- All right, I'm bored. Change it.
- Wait wait, Rick! Hold on.
Even give it a second thought.
That's our slogan.
See it on the bottom of the screen,
below our name.
Here's another slogan,
right below that one.
What are you worried about?
Come get fake doors
Get in here quick,
get out quicker,
with an arm of fake
doors in you arms.
Okay, okay, you can change it.
Don't even worry about it...
I hate Mumunmunundsdays.
And I really could go
for some enchiladas.
Hey Rick, that's pretty cool!
It's just like Garfield, only
instead, it's Gazorpazorpfield.
Hey, isn't Gazorpazorp
where uh...
where those Sex robots
came from, remember?
That whole thing?
Yeah... hey, that's pretty, pretty...
that's true.
That's right!
Yeah. Let's watch some
more Gazorpazorpfield!
Hey Jon, it's me,
Gazorpazorpfield.
Boy. [BLEEP] you, Jon.
You [BLEEP] dumb, stupid, idiot.
Come on, Gazorpazorpfield,
go easy on me, huh?
You dumb, stupid, weak,
pathetic, white, white... uh, uh...
...guilt, white guilt,
milquetoast piece of human garbage.
Jeez, Gazorpazorpfield,
thats, you know...
you're pretty mean to me,
but that takes the cake.
I don't give a [BLEEP]!
I'm Gazorpazorp-[BLEEP]-field, bitch!
Now give me my
[BLEEP] enchiladas!
Hey, Rick, you know, did they
use Bill Murray for this?
Sounds a lot like Bill Murray.
No, Morty, it's Lorenzo Music.
In this reality, he's still alive.
Oh, okay, was his
name Lorenzo Music?
Yeah, I'm pretty sure.
He also did that voice of that
one guy from Ghostbusters.
Which is really strange,
because it's the same character
Bill Murray played
in the movie.
But then, when they
made the movie...
Bill Murray did the voice of
Gazorpazorp... or Garfield, I mean.
Yeah, that's pretty cool, Rick. So all
that happened in this reality too?
I don't know. Just making
conversation with you, Morty.
What do you think? I-I-I-I
know everything about everything?
Did you really talk me
out of the abortion?
Well, we... we blew a tire
on the way to the clinic.
I think, in my head,
I was doing it all for the kids.
And now the first kid is going to
do something with turquoise.
What is either code for crystal meth,
or a gateway to it.
So we didn't do the kids
any favors.
So, we should stay together for each
other and ourselves, or...
Or?
Man. Woman.
And now trunk men?
We know science has created
men that have a trunk
that allows them to have sex with
both male and female partners.
But we don't like the idea
of these people getting married.
Put a line in the sand
everybody..., people!
Vote no on proposition XW2.
The act that says
that gay... uh... trunk
people can get married.
Who needs it?
Not on my watch!
Paid for by Michael Dennys
and The Denny Singers.
Hi, I'm a trunk person.
And I want...
I-I feel love in my heart, too,
just like you.
I want to be able to express
that love, with both a man and a woman.
And I won't be able to...
If Denny and The Denny Singers
get their way.
Hey, let the trunk people
have sex and get married, huh?
Paid for by...
Trunk People.
Oh, I love me
Strawberry Smiggles!
Ooh, I hope nobody ever
gets my hands on me,
and tries to steal my
Strawberry Smiggles.
I'm going to eat every last
one of them, because...
and then they'll
be in my stomach,
and nobody will ever be able
to eat them.
Except for me, because they're
going to be all inside my stomach.
I'm... my name is Mister...
Top Hat Jones,
and God forbid anyone ever take
my sniggy, little pig-dul... smiggles.
I'm keeping 'em all for me.
Last bite.
Oh, now they are all resting
comfortably in my stomach.
Ooh, am I feeling good.
No!
Get away from me!
Get away from me and
my Strawberry Smiggles! No!
Jesus Christ!
It hurts!
My entrails are out!
Why would you even
want to eat these?
They're soaked with
my stomach acid!
Oh, Jesus Christ!
Lord and savior and spirit!
Save me!
Take me to the light!
Oh, my God, I see Demons!
I see demons are coming!
Jeez, Rick. Oh my god!
That's some pretty hardcore stuff,
you know, for a cereal commercial.
Well, you know, Morty, I mean,
you want to sell boxes of cereal,
you gotta, you gotta,
pump the gas a little.
Pedal to the metal, Morty.
In a world, where muscular mannies,
are coming, and they're coming strong,
there's only three...
unmuscular... Michaels.
Get down!
Hurry, run!
And that's when real
turbulent juice is coming,
and you gotta take care of it.
With turbulent juice,
Turmulent tables.
No room is safe from the
turbulent power of turbulent juice.
- What in the hell?
- Sex sells, Morty.
Sex sells what? Was that a movie,
or like, does it clean stuff?
Hey, Dad.
W-w-what's going on?
Oh, your mother and I are going to
be spending some time apart, Morty.
And your sister found out
she was an unwanted pregnancy.
W-w-w-what?
Speaking of "w-w-what", Morty...
W-w-what should we watch next?
What about this?
Baby Legs,
you're a good detective...
but not good enough,
because of your baby legs.
So I'm partnering you up
with Regular Legs.
- Hey there.
- Detective, I'm...
this is upsetting to
me, because I feel
like I don't need no
regular-leg partner.
Baby Legs,
don't talk back to me.
Good luck you two, there's
a criminal to kill.
Wow, you sure found
this guy quick!
Uh, yeah, because I'm
a good detective.
Look, Baby Legs,
it's the criminal!
[BLEEP], I'm the killer.
I'm running, running real quick...
Baby Legs, here we go!
That's the sound I make,
when I'm trying to run fast.
All right, I'm not
going to get him.
I'm, I-I just learned a
real valuable lesson.
I'm coming, Baby Legs!
I'm... Regular Legs!
- We got him!
- Hey, that was good team work.
Baby Legs, and Regular Legs,
I'm proud of you two for working
together, and Baby Legs,
I know it was hard for you to come to
the conclusion that you need a partner.
- But I'm proud of you that you did it.
- Hey thanks, chief!
Now get the [BLEEP] out of here!
Pretty cool, huh, Morty?
Oh.
Uh, I thought it was cool.
I don't give a [BLEEP]
what you think, Jerry.
Hey, uh...
Y-Y-Y-You doin' okay?
I-I-I kind of know how
you feel, Summer.
No, you don't.
You're the little brother.
You're not the cause of
your parents' misery.
You're just a symptom of it.
- Can I show you something?
- Morty, no offense,
but a drawing of me you made
when you were 8
isn't gonna make make me feel
like less of an accident.
That, out there?
That's my grave.
Wait, what?
On one of our adventures, Rick and I
basically destroyed the whole world.
So we bailed on that reality,
and we came to this one.
Because in this one, the
world wasn't destroyed.
And in this one, we were dead.
So we came here, a-a-and we buried
ourselves, and we took their place.
And every morning, Summer,
I eat breakfast,
20 yards away from my
own rotting corpse.
So, you're not my brother?
I'm better than your brother.
I'm a version of your brother
you can trust when he says,
"Don't run".
Nobody exists on purpose,
nobody belongs anywhere...
...everybody's gonna die.
Come watch TV.
Mrs. Sullivan always planned
to leave everything to her cats.
But sometimes, plans need
a helping paw.
What are the kitties to do, but
buckle together and work as a team.
Mrs. Sullivan, I, uh... please
forgive me for being forward.
But your eyes are so beautiful!
Wait, this is an actual movie?
This fall... sparks will fly!
Mrs... Oh... Sullivan...
Between one guy, who
can't get a break...
There's something about you,
Mrs. Sullivan.
...and 9 cats who
break all the rules.
Last Will and Testa-meow:
Weekend at Dead Cat Lady's House 2.
Well, somebody in Hollywood
just lost their job.
Written and
directed by Jerry Smith.
I wrote and directed that?
What am I, nuts?
Hey Morty, you just missed a preview
for your Dad's "Citizen Kane".
Doesn't matter.
Hey, if your, uh, mother
and I had to split custody...
- ...who would you guys choose?
- Doesn't matter.
Breaking News: Academy
Award-winning actor Jerry Smith
is leading police
on a slow-speed pursuit
after suffering an
apparent breakdown.
- Don't even think about it.
- Come on, Jer-
Are you kidding me, Jerry?
It's just a bunch of
dumb tabloid crap.
It's my life,
and we're watching it.
You did it, Beth.
You really nailed it.
You're a surgeon.
A human surgeon.
Yay... you win.
Where the hell am I going?
What are you asking
me for Jerry?
I'm sitting here
trying to figure out
why the cops don't
just take you out.
They got a clear
shot to your head.
I can't believe our tax
dollars pay for this.
Jerry?
Jerry Smith?
Beth Sanchez, I have been
in love with you since high school.
I hate acting, I hate cocaine,
I hate Kristen Stewart.
I wish you hadn't gotten
that abortion,
and I never stopped thinking
about what might've been.
Hey, Ball Fondlers?
Huh? Ball Fondlers?
- Yeah, I could go for some Ball Fondlers.
- Yeah, Ball Fondlers.
Ha-ha, Hamster-in-Butt-World
Weather is done,
and now it's sports time,
coming up.
- Oh, hello there!
- Good day to you, Miss.
So the hamsters live inside
the rectums of those people?
Yeah, sweetie, that's
where they live.
Well, how does that work?
I mean, do the butts look like little
apartments inside?
Yeah! And can they like, leave the butt,
and walk around on their own?
Look, I don't know! I'm watching
the same thing you guys are.
Grandpa Rick, if they leave the butt,
and the person wanders off...
How would they find their butt
person again?
I don't know, Summer! I can't even
hear the TV!
All right, that's it. We're
just gonna go there,
so you idiots can ask your
stupid questions all day.
Ooh! Family vacation!
Translated back from Portuguese
by paulo loppes
Corrections by TPBfan
Tweaking by XhmikosR
www.addic7ed.com