Corrections by XhmikosR
www.addic7ed.com
This is just sloppy
craftsmanship.
Hey, Rick.
Boy, sure is really especially
beautiful out there today, huh?
Oh, yes, Morty. It's almost
unbelievable, isn't it?
Yeah, you know?
There's something about the air
and just the way the sunshine is.
Uh, sure, buddy. Yeah.
Sure. Brilliant.
- Very convincing.
- Convincing?
Oh. Responsive, too.
In real time. I love it.
Uhh... okay.
I'm going to work.
Morty, good morning.
Dad, good morning.
I am going to work. Goodbye.
- What's with mom?
- Oh, what's with mom?
So, you're saying that she's
acting weird?
How sophisticated.
Careful, guys.
You're gonna burn out the CPU
with this one.
Okay, you know what, Rick?
You're acting weird, too.
Whatever,
quote-unquote "Morty."
All right, well...
I'll see you after school.
Ow! Oof! Ugh!
Damn it!
I'm all right. I'm okay.
All right, who can tell me
what 5 x 9 is?
Morty?
Uh, me?
What is 5 x 9?
Umm... you know, it's
uhh... at least 40.
Morty, that's exactly correct!
5 x 9 is at least 40!
Come up here.
Whoo! Way to go, Morty!
Everybody, this is the best
student.
I want you to be
the teacher today.
Teach us, Morty!
Interesting.
What do you want
me to teach you?
Ooh, ooh!
How do you make concentrated
dark matter?
Oh, that's a good question.
Concentrated huh?
Concentrated dark matter the fuel
for accelerated space travel.
Now, do you know how to make it?
Umm...
Come on, Morty.
Isn't your grandpa, like,
a scientist?
Oh, yeah, but, you
know, he told me
that I shouldn't go
around spouting off about,
you know, his science and stuff.
I bet you've seen him make
concentrated dark matter a lot.
You know, if you tell us, I'll
be your girlfriend.
Uh, y-you will?
Seems like a rare
opportunity, Morty.
Morty, u-uh, come on.
- There's a family emergency.
- Stop right there!
If he leaves, I'm
giving him an "F".
- He doesn't care.
- Aw, man!
Rick, I have to go back!
I think I was about to get
married!
Ugh!
Take a shower with me, Morty.
- What?!
- Listen to me, Morty.
Get your clothes off and get in
the shower right now.
You got to trust me, Morty.
Ugh!
I'm gonna get an "F"
in class, Rick.
Morty, that's not class.
That wasn't your teacher.
This isn't your school.
This entire world
is not the world.
We're inside a huge simulation
chamber on an alien spaceship.
Wait a minute.
W-what are you talking about?
It's all fake, Morty all of it.
Nanobotic renderings, a bunch of
crazy fake nonsense, Morty.
I couldn't say so until we got
in the shower.
They won't monitor us in here.
Monitor us?! W-who?!
Zigerion scammers, Morty.
The galaxy's most ambitious,
least successful con artists.
You know, it's lucky for us
they're also really
uncomfortable with nudity.
Aw, come on, Rick.
If everyone's just
gonna be insane today,
at least let me be
insane with Jessica.
I can't let you do that, Morty.
Give it to me!
No!
You give it to me!
G-g-give it! No, Rick!
Oh, God, sir!
They're still naked!
Ugh.
Well, check every five quintons
and tell me when they're not.
I think we should make Kevin
look, sir.
What?! No!
Why would you even say that?
Uh, sir, we have a situation
over here.
If there's a wiener on that monitor,
I swear to God, stu...
Something is drawing a lot of
processing power.
Oh, wait. No wonder.
There's another real human in
the simulator.
Okay, Jerry big pitch meeting.
Make-or-break time.
You can do this.
How did this happen?!
Where's the abductions
department?
Hey, man, abductions just
follows the acquisition order.
Don't put this on acquisitions!
We only acquire humans that
haven't been simulated!
Well, simulations doesn't simulate
anybody that's been abducted, so...
Oh, I see! Oh, oh!
It was no one's fault.
Oh, okay.
I'm sorry.
Well, then, problem solved.
Oh, wait no.
There's still another
human in here!
Who is he?
Rick's son-in-law, Jerry Smith.
So far, he hasn't noticed he's
in a simulation.
Well, cap his sector
at 5% processing,
keep his settings on auto, and
we'll deal with him later.
Rick Sanchez is the target.
Got to relax.
It's just a pitch.
This is earth radio.
And now, here's... human music.
Hmm. Human music.
I like it.
Rick!
Uhp, uhp, uhp!
Morty, keep your hands off your
ding-dong!
It's the only way we
can speak freely.
Look around you, Morty.
Do you really think
this world is real?
You'd have to be an idiot not to
notice all the sloppy details.
Look that guy's putting a bun
between two hot dogs.
I don't know, Rick.
I mean, I've seen
people do that before.
Well, look at that old lady.
She's she's walking a cat on
a leash.
Uh, Mrs. Spencer does
that all the time, Rick.
Look, I-I-I don't want to hear
about Mrs. Spencer, Morty!
She's an idiot!
All right, all right, there.
What about that, Morty?
Okay, okay, you got me
on that one.
Oh, really, Morty?
Are you sure you haven't seen that
somewhere in real life before?
No, no.
I haven't seen that.
I mean, why would a pop tart want
to live inside a toaster, Rick?
I mean, that would be, like, the
scariest place for them to live.
You know what I mean?
You're missing the point, Morty.
Why would he drive a smaller
toaster with wheels?
I mean, does your car look like
a smaller version of your house?
No.
So, why are they doing this?
W-what do they want?
Well, that would be
obvious to you, Morty, if you'd
been paying attention.
We got the President of the
United States in here!
We need 10cc of concentrated
dark matter, stat, or he'll die!
Concentrated dark matter?
They were asking
about that in class.
Yeah, it's a special fuel
I invented to travel
through space faster
than anybody else.
These zigerions are always
trying to scam me out of my secrets,
but they made a big
mistake this time, Morty.
They dragged you into this.
- Now they're gonna pay!
- What do you...
What are we gonna do?
We'll scam the scammers, Morty.
And we're gonna take them for
everything they've got.
National apple farmers of America,
welcome to our ad agency.
I'm Jerry Smith.
All right.
I'll just... get to the pitch.
Um, simple question, gentlemen,
what are apples?
Excuse me.
What are apples?
Apples are food.
And... when do we need food?
When we're hungry.
With that, I give you
your new slogan!
Well, say something!
- Do you like it?
- Yes.
- You do?
So... I sold it?
I sold the idea?
- Yes.
- Oh, my God! Thank you!
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Hey!
I just sold my first pitch!
Slow down!
Lookin' good.
My man!
Hello.
Guess who just sold
the apples campaign.
Who just sold the
apples campaign?
Me!
I guess it wasn't a rip-off of
"got milk?" after all.
- Guess someone was wrong.
- Yes.
Well, all is forgiven,
because right now,
I've got an erection the size of an
east coast lighthouse,
and I'm coming home to share
it with my beautiful wife.
- Okay.
- Wait really?
- Yes.
- Yes!
See you in 10 minutes!
Hey!
I'm going to make
love to my wife!
Lookin' good.
- Slow down!
- My man!
Aw, geez, Rick. I don't know
if I like this plan, you know?
I mean, crowds, they have a
tendency to make me really nervous.
Morty, relax.
It's just a bunch of 1s and 0s
out there.
You're gonna be fine.
Just follow my lead.
Yo, deejay, drop that beat.
Uh-oh, Morty.
This crowd looks too small for
one of our famous rap concerts.
I don't think we can
perform our new song,
"the recipe for
concentrated dark matter",
for a crowd this tiny.
You got that right, Rick.
Now that's more like it!
Morty, here we go.
Let me hear everybody say
"hey-oh!" Yeah!
All the ladies say, "yeah!"
Everybody over 30, do this with
your hands!
Everybody with a red shirt,
jump up and down!
Yeah, don't move.
Yo, everyone whose
first name begins with an "L"
who isn't hispanic, walk in a
circle the same number of times
as the square root of your age
times 10!
Run, Morty!
Before the system reboots!
Yeah! You like that?
Now who's unremarkable?
You hungry for apples?
Are you hungry...
for... apples?!
Oh, my God.
That's the best sex I've ever
had in my life.
It's... it's... too good.
I don't deserve this, Beth.
I'm a fraud.
Oh, man, Rick!
Where we running to?
Out of the simulation, Morty.
Normally, the chamber operates
like a treadmill,
with the virtual world disappearing
behind us and being
rendered in front of us as we move
through it, but while it's frozen, Morty,
we can get to...
The edge.
Here we go.
Holy crap!
Come on, Morty.
Sir, they're over the edge.
Yes, they are.
Just... as... planned.
Oh, this is going
to be such a mind-
Keep your eyes peeled for the
central processing room, Morty.
That's how we're gonna scam
these idiots.
So, hey, why do these
aliens keep coming after you, Rick,
if you're so much
smarter than them?
It's an obsession for
them at this point.
The zigerions have been trying
to outsmart me for years, Morty.
Every time they do, I'm one step
ahead of them.
Aha!
Here we go.
Grab as many processors as you
can carry, Morty.
These guys aren't good at much,
but they're really good
at making these chips.
I've got so many, I can
barely hold them all.
Look at look at this.
Oops. I dropped one.
Don't worry about it, Morty.
There's plenty of them,
you little goofball.
Come here, Morty! Oh, I gotcha!
Come on, quit it, Rick!
Quit it!
Nothing wrong with
just a little bit of horseplay
every now and
then, little fella.
Wow. What do you know?
Huh. That was easy.
Totes malotes, dawg.
Just kind of hard to
believe, you know?
Believe it, Morty.
And once again, I'm flying away
with everything I can carry,
and the zigerions got
nothing of mine.
Mr. Marklevitz, do you have a...
minute to talk?
Yes.
Look, I'm a fraud.
I mean, let's face it,
"hungry for apples" is just a
rip-off of "got milk?"
It's almost identical.
- Yes.
- Okay.
I deserve that.
Umm... I guess... I'll just pack
up my desk.
Yes.
Oh, my God.
Wait. You know what?! No!
The milk people don't have a patent
on simple rhetorical questions!
There's not even a single word
in "hungry for apples" that's
shared by "got milk?".
It's a completely
different slogan.
It's different!
And I shouldn't be fired.
- I should be promoted!
- Yes.
Yeah!
Wait. Really?
- Yes.
- Yes!
I mean, I'm it may be derivative,
but it's the most
successful campaign to come out
- of this agency in a long time.
- Yes.
I'm not saying it
should win an award for commercials,
but it could certainly be nominated
for an award for commercials
specifically about apples,
like... an appley or something.
Yes.
Is there really an award called the
appley for apple-related ad campaigns?
Yes.
- Could we nominate me?
- Yes.
Holy crap!
Get in, Morty.
I'm gonna be able to
use these processors
to make some real
important science stuff.
Huh.
I thought I entered
the code right.
Wha well, what's this?
What could this possibly be?
Because it looks like you're
inside a simulation...
Inside a simulation.
You're still on the ship.
Game-day bucket go boom.
Sir, the, uh, doctor's
appointment to examine
the discoloration on
your butthole flaps was-
Too loud, Cynthia.
Too loud and too specific.
We've known how to make concentrated
dark matter for a long time.
But now we also know the code to
your fabled safe, Rick Sanchez!
All your most valuable secrets
will now be ours!
Uh, yeah, until I
get home before you,
and change the combination,
you bunch of idiots!
That is why you're never
getting home.
Get them!
Run, Morty!
Oh, my God!
Ow!
I got to tell you, this morning,
I didn't even know
this award existed.
Now I'm holding one.
And... um...
Look, I want to say that today
was the best day of my life...
But... the truth is, it's
more meaningful than that.
My man!
Yes. Thank you, sir.
I... am... finally complete!
My my my my man!
What the hell?!
No.
- Jerry?!
- Dad!
What are you doing here?
Why are you dressed
like a waiter?
Screw it. We don't have time.
- Come on.
- No!
Ohhhhh!
Aah!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Oof!
Man up, Jerry!
I may need you to
work the lasers.
Oh, man!
They're hot on our tail, Rick!
I guess they really do
have concentrated dark matter.
Well, you know how to
make it, too, right, Rick?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Uh, check the engine room.
We just need cesium, plutonic
quarks, and bottled water.
It's all here, Rick!
Wow, Morty.
Lucky break.
Grab that bucket.
Okay, two parts plutonic quarks,
one part cesium.
Okay. Uh-huh.
All right.
Now empty the water
bottle into the bucket
and pour it all into the fuel tank
so we can get the hell out of here!
What are you doing, Morty?!
There's no time!
Oh, no.
What the-
No!
Oh, my God, Rick.
How dumb are you?
You're inside a simulation...
Of a simulation...
Inside another giant simulation!
We never had the recipe for
concentrated dark matter.
But we do now!
We do now, sucka!
You simulated my
grandson's genitalia?!
You bunch of diabolical sons
of bitches!
Kevin fought real hard to
supervise that project.
You said you weren't gonna
tell anyone!
I'm never gonna live this down,
am I?
All right. Okay.
All right, great. Wonderful.
You win. Can we go home now?
I don't know. Can you?
Ha! Nice.
Okay, okay.
Show this gullible
turd to his shuttle.
I'm done with him.
Oh, wait. Let me get a picture.
Aww. Look at his face.
He's trying to figure out if
he's in a simulation still.
Are you, Rick?
Are you?
You're not.
Or are you?
Oh, and, by the way, I don't
have discolored butthole flaps.
That was part of the simulation.
Oh.
Uh, sir, should I cancel that
appointment, then?
Yeah! Of course you should!
No, keep it.
Move it up, actually,
if you can.
Hey, Jerry, don't worry
about it.
So what if the most meaningful
day of your life was...
a simulation operating
at minimum capacity?
You know what, Rick?
Those guys took you
for a ride, too.
You should try having a little respect
for the dummies of the universe,
now that you're one of us.
Maybe you're right, Jerry.
Maybe you're right.
All right, everybody.
Two parts plutonic quarks...
One part cesium...
And listen, I'm sorry for
yelling earlier.
I couldn't ask for
a better staff.
I love you guys, and I love all
your families.
And the final ingredient...
Whoa!
What the hell?!
What happened back there?
Why don't you ask the smartest
people in the universe, Jerry?
Oh, yeah. You can't.
They blew up.
So...
What do you think?
You're fired.
Wha-
But this idea was tested in a
state-of-the-art simulation.
Well, then, it was a
terrible simulation.
Get out.
Man, how does a guy like that go
home and have sex with his wife?
Hey, Morty.
What?
Hey, little buddy.
How you doing in here right now?
Aw, geez, Rick.
What are you doing, man?
You're a good kid, Morty.
You're a real little
character, Morty.
Oh, boy.
You know, I had a really
rocky road today, Morty.
You're my little
friend, aren't you?
We had some good times
together, Morty?
You're a real true
hero out in the field.
You're a real trouper,
huh, Morty?
Have you been drinking, Rick?
I really appreciate you, Morty.
Okay, cool.
All right, Rick you
little son of a bitch!
Are you a simulation?!
Huh?! Are you a simulation?!
No! No! No!
You little son of a bitch!
I'm sorry, Morty.
You're a good
you're a good kid, Morty.
Geez!
You're a good
you're a good kid.
Oh, my God!
What the hell?
What a life.
Corrections by XhmikosR
www.addic7ed.com