Corrections by XhmikosR
www.addic7ed.com
d last king Christmas d
d last arrived d
d on the Christmas d
d Christmas d
Mmm.
Jerry, you are really
giving it to this ham.
Um, merry Christmas.
Hello?
My parents are coming over for
the first time in years.
Can we stow the gadgets
and look alive?
Alive?
For your parents?
- Mm, good one.
- Hey, man!
You "hey, man!"
This holiday is about humanity.
You know, I thought it was about
being born half-God or something.
Whatever.
All electronic items are going
in the stocking now.
Dad, I'm not giving
you my phone.
Put it in the stocking, Summer,
or I'm joining Facebook.
A-ho, ho, ho,
everybody.
More like "whoa, whoa, whoa."
What is this?
My parents are coming!
Calm down, Jerry.
This is Reuben, an old friend.
Pearl harbor.
I check in on him once a year and give
him a little medical evaluation.
Aww!
Dad, that is so sweet!
Yeah, it is.
I don't get it.
Korea.
Don't worry about your
Christmas, Jerry.
I'll be with Reuben in my workshop
while you guys are having another day
in Phil Collins' proverbial paradise.
Huh.
You think you know a guy.
Okay, there's my parents.
Now, remember no TV, no
phones, no laptops.
We are connecting this Christmas,
like old-school Jews on a Saturday.
- Hey, hey!
- Merry Christmas, son.
Uh, hi.
Can I help you?
Jerry, this is Jacob.
Didn't you get our text message?
No!
You must be Jerry.
That's a fine-looking apron.
- Williams-sonoma?
- I wish!
But thank you.
So, you're a...
friend of the family?
Uh, the way we see it, he's a
part of the family.
Wow.
After your father's brush
with cancer and losing your Uncle,
we looked at life and wondered,
how have we spent it,
and how do we spend
the rest of it?
What are we going to
be when we die...
a list of fears and questions or a
collection of real experiences?
Holy crap.
Joyce, that's amazing.
Then Jacob came into our lives,
and... we're learning to
live again.
All three of us.
Cool.
- Eggnog?
- Now we are talking!
This man's got the apron
and the eggnog, huh?
Hi, Joyce. Leonard.
- Hello, there.
- Merry Christmas, man.
Morty, a moment of your time?
He's in bad shape, Morty.
Aw, geez, Rick.
What'd you do?
Gee, thanks, Morty.
What kind of monster do you
think I am?
I'm sitting here trying to
save the guy's life.
I need your help.
I want you to find
Dr. Xenon Bloom.
He'll know what's going on.
Uh, where
where do I find Dr. Bloom?
In Reuben.
- Reuben, Minnesota?
- Reuben on the table, Morty.
Look, I don't have time for you to wrap
your little walnut around everything.
Just hold your breath
until the process
is over or your lungs
will collapse.
What proc-
- Hey, dad, where's Morty?
- He's busy.
Morty, can you hear me?
Head north.
Rick, where am I?
Depending on my aim, you should
be just South of the entrance.
Entrance to what?
Welcome, Morty.
Welcome...
...to anatomy park!
It's a little business venture
I've been cooking up on the side
with Dr. Bloom an amusement
park inside a human body.
Science isn't cheap, Morty.
This should really help put a
dent in the overhead.
Oh, my God!
This is insane!
Spleen Mountain?
Bladder falls?
Pirates of the pancreas?
You got a problem with
that last one, Morty?
Huh? No, no.
I'm just reading 'em out loud in
the order that I'm seeing 'em.
Okay. All right.
If I sounded a little defensive,
it's because...
pirates of the pancreas was my
baby.
You know, I got I got a lot of
pushback when I pitched it, Morty.
I guess I'm still a little
defensive.
Let's just find Dr. Bloom,
all right?
I'm picking up a distress
signal in the liver, Morty.
Proceed to the liver.
Arriving at...
...liver.
Ow!
Mind the gap.
It's really scary in here, Rick.
The liver's under maintenance.
Reuben's seen some rough years,
Morty.
Don't judge.
You don't agree to have a theme park built
inside you if your life's going great.
Rick! It's a monster!
No, no, no. Morty.
The only monster here is
alco...... holism.
That is an animatronic werewolf.
Who are you?!
Answer me!
Where'd you come from?
My my my grandpa Rick sent me!
Poncho!
That's quite enough.
Morty, that's Poncho.
This is Roger and Annie.
And I am Dr. Xenon Bloom.
Hey, Bloom, it's Rick.
What the hell's going on here?
I don't know why, but the
entire security system has shut down,
and I'm afraid... the
exhibits are unlocked.
Exhibits?
Anatomy park's greatest attraction,
young man, isn't the
music or the food or the...
Pirates of the pancreas.
Watch it.
It is, first and foremost,
a living museum of humanity's most
noble and ferocious diseases.
Diseases?
Hey, doc.
I got news for you.
Your living museum is officially
a wild safari!
Hepatitis A! Run!
Oh, the food goes in
your mouth, girl.
Oh, Jacob.
I'm sorry, Jacob.
I guess I'm still confused
about the precise nature and
origin of your relationship with
my parents.
Are you, like, uh are you,
like, their caretaker?
Is that what it is?
- We can go into detail later, son.
- Now, wait.
Th-there's no point to secrecy.
Let's all live and die honestly.
Your mother and I have shared
40 years of each other, mind,
body, and soul, and when minds
and souls are joined for
eternity and when eternity is
at the door, it's an invitation
to let go of the body and an
opportunity to share and experiment.
Dad, please.
What are you saying?
Whatever it is, it's beautiful,
Leonard, and we support you.
Hey, speak for
yourself, because it...
sounds like you're about to
say Jacob is your lover.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Jacob is your mother's lover.
I watch them sometimes...
from a chair and sometimes from a closet,
almost always dressed as superman.
Oh.
Jerry, this ham has got to be
all you, right?
It's incredible.
Happy human holiday, dad.
Aah!
Hepatitis won't follow us
into the respiratory system.
That's strange.
Airflow is down 20%.
So, the brain isn't getting
enough oxygen.
That's why security's offline.
Well, I guess we
better check it out.
Hey! Wait for me!
Put that back on!
If we got up to the bronchial catwalk,
we could look for a blockage.
I'll go.
- Don't be a hero, kid.
- I'm not.
I'm doing it because it's fun.
We shouldn't be here.
Whatever you do, do not fire
that thing in here.
We must save Reuben.
This is my life's work.
It's all right, my dear.
Nearly all human lungs contain...
a strain of these bacteria, but
the scar tissue keeps them...
Dormant.
- Morty, get down!
- Whoa-ho-ho!
Whoa!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Oh, what are those things?
Tuberculosis coming in fast!
Not faster than a bullet!
Aah!
No!
Do you know what you've done?!
Whoa!
Get to the digestive tract!
He's coughing!
Whoaaaa!
Don't let me die!
Just take a deep breath, Reuben.
You're not gonna die!
What's your name?
My name is...
Alexand-
Rick r-r-Reuben's
got tuberculosis!
Oh, great work, Morty.
Okay, I'll just
cure it and then-
Okay.
Well, I can't cure death.
This is bad, Morty.
You're trapped in a dead man.
Listen, if the situation
keeps darkening,
do yourself a favor and pop
by pirates of the pancreas.
Obviously I'm biased, but I
think it's great, Morty.
It's a bunch of Pirates
running around a Pancreas.
We don't whitewash
it, either, Morty.
I mean, the pirates
are really rapey.
The top priority is to get, you
know, you guys out of there,
but I'm just saying, if that
becomes impossible,
please, you gotta
treat yourself.
Oh, man.
What is that horrible smell?
You mean the panda express?
Kidding. I-I'm kidding.
The body is beginning to
constrict and fill with gas.
We're inside a corpse, my boy.
Anatomy park is doomed.
Forget about the park, doctor!
How do we get out?
The digestive tract is the
evacuation route.
Get it?
There's an emergency station in
the colon with a ray that can
enlarge us all.
Everybody, head for the colon!
Now I'm taking orders from a
12-year-old boy?
Morty, the scar sacs containing
the tuberculosis were sabotaged.
This disaster was an inside job.
Keep your eye on Annie.
She was written up several times by
her manager at the churro stand.
Intestines are ahead to the left,
then to the right, then
left, et cetera.
Hey, just so you know,
I'm actually 14.
So, you know...
What?
- Not 12.
- Okay.
You know, because he
just said I was 12.
Oh.
Good for you.
Oof. Ugh. Morty.
Strike one.
d It's a road of wonder d
d a trail of food d
d it's a pathway to break up d
d the bad and good d
d it's a tube that digests d
d and then sends out the rest d
d it's a small, small d
d intestine d
It goes on like this for miles.
Then we get to the large
intestine!
Shh!
I hear something.
Don't move.
Gonorrhea can't see us if we
don't move.
Wait, I was wrong.
I was thinking of a T. Rex.
Move!
We're sitting ducks!
Doc, didn't you say that the
body was filling with gas?
- Yes. Why?
- Kid, you're a genius.
Are you mad?!
Everybody, in here!
Hey, gonorrhea!
How's this for a burning
sensation?
Huh.
d Drummer drum drum d
d drum drum drum d
d drum drum drum drum drum
drum d
d Christmas drums d
Oh, sing it, Summer.
d being played by a Bo-o-o-y d
Oh, I love to hear you sing.
Jerry, come on.
This is what you wanted.
I get it, Beth.
Be careful what you wish for.
I'm being punished for taking
your iPad.
What?
Jerry, let that stuff go, okay?
I'm sorry I was a bitch earlier.
Let's just be here.
- Summer!
- Ethan?
What are you doing here?
I've been texting you for hours!
What the hell?!
I don't have my phone!
I'm doing a human holiday!
Well, did you even consider
how that might make me feel?!
How you feel?!
Why is everything always
happening to you?!
Summer, do you have a boyfriend?
Yeah, do you, Summer?
I don't know, Ethan.
Do I?!
Jerry, no disrespect, but you really need
to connect more with your family, man.
I should be able to access...
the backup generator to get the
growth ray online.
If it works, we'll be
regular-sized in a few minutes.
I just hope Reuben's not in a room
with white carpets or upholstery.
- What the hell is that?
- The sphincter dam.
We built it when Reuben
became incontinent,
but it was not designed
to hold a corpse load.
I've almost got it.
Everybody, move
inside the circle.
Poncho?
What is this in your backpack?
That's bubonic plague!
What are you doing with that,
Poncho?
Everybody, get back!
Poncho, you son of a bitch!
You released the tuberculosis
so you could steal from me?
That's right, baby.
A lot of people would pay top
dollar to decimate the population.
I'll take the highest bidder...
Al-qaeda, North Korea, Republicans,
shriners, balding men that work out,
people on the Internet
that are only turned on...
by cartoons of
Japanese teenagers.
Anything is better than working
for you, you pompous, negligent,
iTunes-gift-card-as-a-holiday-
bonus-giving mother-
Come on!
Aah!
Get off!
You guys!
It's gonna burst! Go!
Go, go, go!
- My foot is stuck.
- No!
It's okay!
It's okay. Just go.
Tell my family I love them.
They may be hard to
find 'cause my wife...
kept her last name and
she made the kids take it, too,
so, I-I don't know, you can-
No!
Let me ask you a
question, Ethan.
Where's the anger
coming from, man?
From Summer being a total bitch!
Where's the anger coming from?
My brother... took me fishing
once... in the bushes...
I can't... I can't...
He made me feel like a girl!
He made me a girl!
He didn't make you
anything, man.
You are who you are.
She is who she is.
Now, you go to her... brand-new.
Come here, right now.
Oh, my God.
I'm so sorry, Ethan!
I love you!
I love you so much.
Um...
You did it again, cubbie.
Come here.
No! Stop! I hate this!
Well, Christmas doesn't revolve
around what you hate, son.
Well, then I hate Christmas!
Enjoy being human!
You guys are gross and lame.
My name's Reuben Ridley.
You're inside me right now,
but by the end of this journey...
Whoopsie.
I'll be inside all of you.
My story begins during the dot-com
crash in the early '90s.
You can put your fingers
wherever you want.
Morty, you want to put
it on mute or something?
I'm I'm trying to concentrate.
Uh... Rick?
Not now, Jerry.
I've got much, much
smaller fish to fry.
I wanted to say I'm
sorry I ever judged you.
Right now, you're
my sanest relative.
Relative.
Relative size!
Jerry, hand me a scalpel and a
bundle of dynamite.
Morty, can you get
to the left nipple?
Are you kidding?
I'm hoping I can get to both of
'em, Rick.
No, Morty, I'm talking
about Reuben's left nipple.
We need to get to
the left nipple!
The body is decaying.
The arterial transit
system is useless.
We can try the service shuttle.
It's connected to the skeletal
system.
That's why we call it the bone
train.
Would you like to ride the
bone train, miss?
If it'll get us out of here.
How about you, Morty?
Would you like to
ride the bone train?
Why are you doing this bit?
We're gonna die! Let's go!
Well... I can see
you're busy.
Merry Christmas, Rick.
There's no autopilot.
One of us will have to stay here
and operate it manually.
Uh, well...
No, you're you're right.
It was a dick move for me to
even pause like that.
This is all my fault.
You go on.
What the hell is that?
E. Coli outbreak.
Hurry!
- Wait, there is an autopilot.
- Wait!
It's okay! Never mind!
I wanted to sacrifice
myself anyway!
They're they're chewing
through the doors!
We're in the areola,
Rick, almost to the nipple,
but we're also in a
really bad situation!
I'm almost there, Morty!
Reports from all over the
country have been coming in
about what appears to be...
a giant, naked man over the
continental United States.
We now go to Tom
Randolph in New York.
Tom?
Well, the eyes aren't twinkling
and the dimples aren't merry,
but I'm standing under a nose
like a 70-mile cherry.
Thank you, Tom.
Let's go now to Eric
McMahan in Los Angeles.
We've got feet here on
the west coast, Bill,
giant feet, even relative
to the giant man's size,
and you know what they say
about that.
Well, if the old adage is true,
one can only wonder what's going
down in the rocky mountains.
Wha?
Oh my God, the track!
It's Hepatitis A!
Aaaah!
The nipple hole.
It's beautiful.
- Oh, no!
- Holy crap!
Whoa! It's Hepatitis C!
Um... wait did we have some
sort of relationship with him?
I think they're just like that?
I think they're just good guys.
Oh. Huh.
Where's Dr. Bloom?
I'm sorry, Rick, but he's dead.
God damn it, Morty.
I ask you to do one thing!
Jerry doesn't know what
he's missing.
He'll come around, Beth.
Christmas is a special time.
It has funny ways of bringing
families together.
I don't know, Jacob.
Jerry got an invitation to be
alive today, and he rejected it.
I don't know if our marriage
will...
It's raining blood!
Oh, shit. Find Jerry.
Oh, God.
- Jerry!
- It's all right.
The TV says there's nothing to
worry about.
The giant, naked sky Santa
has exploded.
Blood and chunks of viscera are
raining down on the country.
Everything should be fine.
Oh, yes.
Dad, can I have my phone back?
A sure, sweetie. Here.
Everybody, take a device.
It'll help you relax.
- This is nice.
- Yeah.
Look, I guess we really learned
something this Christmas, Jacob.
No, we didn't, dad.
No, we didn't.
Too bad about Dr. Bloom.
He was a genius the only man capable
of creating a new anatomy park.
Actually, I studied
Dr. Bloom's work.
I believe I have the
knowledge necessary
to create an entirely new,
much safer park.
What about...
Pirates of the pancreas?
I think it was one of the
most underrated attractions.
Boo-yah!
Hold your breath.
Hey, what the hell, Rick?!
What the hell, man! I liked her!
I really had something
going there, Rick!
Yeah, so I heard.
You dodged a bullet,
Morty, trust me.
- Puffy vagina.
- What's wrong with that?
That doesn't sound like a
problem to me.
I don't know.
Come on, let's get
some stuffing.
I'm starving.
Oh, unbelievable.
We got we got a bunch of
robot, computer people,
sitting around with their faces
stuffed into computer screens.
Do you guys realize that Christ
was born today?
Jesus Christ, our savior,
was born today.
Are are are you people
even human?
What kind of Christmas is this?
Hey, Rick?
Rick, can you hear me?
Loud and clear, Annie.
Great.
We're also on with Alejandro,
our chief imaginarian.
Hey, Rick.
Natalie Jacobs and Chris Deseter
from microscopic marketing,
Zack from organ concepts,
and Jamie from new media.
Hey, everybody.
- Hi, how's it going?
- Hi, Rick.
So, pirates of the pancreas.
Yeah. Talk to me.
Hey, Rick.
It's Alejandro speaking.
Um, so, we asked ourselves,
internally we asked
ourselves over here,
"okay, what does a
pancreas do?"
And the answer was,
"does it make pirates?"
No, it makes Insulin, you know?
- So, we're starting with a new-
- Those guys are inside me, huh?
Like, building a park?
Those guys are inside you
building a piece of shit, Ethan!
They're inside you building a
monument to compromise!
Those people.
This whole thing, Ethan.
Cool.
And who pays me?
Corrections by XhmikosR
www.addic7ed.com