Look, I'm not paying 70 smidgens
for a broken defraculator.
That is multiphase
quantum resonator.
- Well, does it defraculate?
- No.
Then it's a broken defraculator.
Like you would even know
dick about fraculation.
Your planet just got cellphones
and the coverage still sucks!
Yeah, yeah, and your
species eat sulfur.
So lets say 60 smidgens.
I tell you what...
I'll do you a favor.
I throw in a fart.
Hey, Rick...
You think maybe I could get
something from this place?
Like a souvenir?
Like just to have, like
something cool, you know?
Not here Morty.
We'll stop somewhere else,
because you know,
there is always another pawn shop.
OK, I just...
You know, I thought that robot over
there, looked pretty cool, you know?
Oh, it looks cool, huh?
- That's why you want it?
- Yeah, you know?
I mean... it's different
from the stuff on earth.
And you know, you take me to all these
crazy places across the galaxy
and you know, I don't
really have anything to...
to remember all those trips by.
It'd be kind of cool like
a souvenir, you know?
Like what if you passed away
or died or something?
I wouldn't even have
anything to remember
all the cool stuff
we did, you know.
Okay, 60 for the resonator
and my grandson wants the sex robot.
Subtitles by Ozymandias
Corrections by XhmikosR
So we're just going to pretend
this isn't happening?
I'm not saying that's a bad idea.
Just asking.
Rick, why did you let Morty
bring that thing into our house?
What do you want from me?
He thought it looked cool,
you know what I mean?
Alright, back to...
back to...
back upstairs.
Well, I'm intervening.
Intervening with puberty?
You'll turn him into Ralph Finnes
in Red Dragon.
He is at that age,
let's just be proud of him.
Jesus, did I really set
the bar that low?
Rick, could you come
with me please?
Quickly!
OK, now if we here squeaking
we intervene.
Where is the sex robot Morty?
That is Gwendoline.
I mean the robot.
She started beeping, and then
transformed and tried to fly away.
Strange.
That's usually the man's job.
You know what I'm
talking about, Morty?
Morty.
That's my catchphrase,
remember?
Remember how I cemented
that catchphrase?
Alright, alright
seriously though.
Let me grab this thing.
Come on.
- Rascal.
- Okay... unacceptable
What is going on?
Alright...
What is that?
I think Morty's robot was designed
for more than long weekends.
Genetic compiler,
incubation chamber.
Yeah, this here is some
kind of baby maker.
And that there is half Morty
and half... who knows... what.
It's my bad guys
I'll take care of it.
Hey listen,
you guys quarantine
the house when Summer
brought olives from Mexico.
This thing could grow
to the size of Delaware.
It might eat brains
and exhale space AIDS.
We gotta be careful.
I lost the chance
to be careful, Rick.
I'm a father now, you know?
It's time for me to be responsible.
Isn't that right...
- Don't name it!
- Morty Jr.?
Oh crap, he named it.
Well Dad, it's a living thing.
And it's half human.
And it was born on America's soil
which entitles it...
Jerry, majoring in civics
was your mistake.
Don't punish us for it.
Fine. I'm gonna take this
thing into my workshop,
and do a little
bit of investigating.
Do not let that thing
out of your sight.
It looks harmless now, but it could
grow into something dangerous.
- Like the Insane Clown Posse.
- Yeah, good one, Jerry.
2003 just called and
wants its easy target back.
He is a like little me.
You don't think he'll turn
into a monster, do you?
They always do.
1995 called, they want...
their "certain year called wanting
its blank back" formula back.
Why, Jerry?
Why expend the effort?
Life is effort,
and I'll stop when I die.
Out.
- What you doing?
- Well, I can't solve...
the problem my way thanks to...
your family's primitive
biological hang ups.
Gross. I might have just touched
one of Morty's loads.
But maybe I can find
suitable parents
for Morty Jr. on this
robot homeworld,
which is...
Gazorpazorp in the
Andromeda system.
- Scoot Summer.
- Don't you need a new companion...
now that Morty is
in the family way?
I don't do adventures
with chicks, Summer.
Oh right, because there is
something about having a wiener...
...that would make me better
walking through a hole?
Oh crap.
Grandpa Rick!
Help!
Still think it's a good idea to go
through a hole without a wiener?
- I wanna go home!
- Yeah, no duh.
Great, now I have to
take over a whole planet
because of your stupid boobs.
You're doing great, Morty.
Really you think? I mean
I'm not doing much of anything.
What do I do if it cries?
Then you put it down
and let it cry itself out.
Yeah, right.
We tried that technique on Summer
and she is gonna end up stripping.
Isn't she?
Yes she is.
She is gonna strip her attention
because she was denied it.
Stop filling it with
your own insecurity.
You're gonna turn
it into Mort...
more... more... more of you.
Well, we can't all be raised
like reptiles
by a mentally-ill scientist.
What the...
Listen to me. I am not
rewarding this behavior.
Knock it off both of you!
Give me him!
Give me my baby!
You're both nuts.
I'm gonna raise Morty Jr. myself.
Where is your hands?
There's your hands.
And that's how we
play happy hands.
Oh, you are going to
ruin that kid, Morty.
At least we can agree on that.
Thanks, dumb dumb.
I said "thanks, dumb dumb".
Go get more.
Summer, put your burqa on!
That burqa is a human rights violation,
and I spent a lot on this top.
Look, I'm trying to repair
portal gun with
with bunch of sex doll parts
and I have to do it one-handed
to keep these belushis from
cutting you off.
The least you could do
is be ashamed of your gender.
What's the deal with this place?
Why is it such a sausage planet
and how did such
backwards idiots invent robots?
Obviously at some point
the Gazorpians became so
evolved that they replaced
females with birthing machines.
The resultant lack of
distraction and handpecking
allowed them to focus
entirely on war,
so they bombed themselves
back to the stone age
and now they just fight
with each other over
fake pussy with sticks
and rocks all day long.
You think it's efficient
to get rid of women?
You ever see a line
for the men's room?
Are you hea... Do you lis...
You hear me, summer?
The... plot... thickens.
You might wanna cover
your eyes, Summer.
Yeah, like it was my
dream to watch.
Summer, grab hold.
Grandpa Rick,
where are we going?
Well obviously Summer, it appears
the lower tier of this society
is being manipulated through
sex and advanced technology
by a hidden ruling class.
Sound familiar?
Ticketmaster.
There we go, Summer.
Hey brother.
Hey bro.
Nice racket you got
going on here.
Listen, I'm Rick Sanchez
from earth dimension C-137.
Don't mean any harm.
Coming in peace.
It's all cool in the...
good in the neighborhood.
That was what I was trying...
That's what I meant.
Oh, I get it.
The old "behind every
great man amazon" twist.
Silence!
Your slave is ill-mannered.
- My slave?
- We assume...
you are from a more
primitive world,
where men are still permitted
to be servants.
If he is a rogue male, tell us now,
and we will kill him.
He's my slave.
He is definitely my slave.
Oh boy, what's the opposite of...
Am I right ladies
and gentlemen?
You guys kidding me.
Morty Jr., you're gonna be a special
little guy, aren't you?
You're my special little guy.
DA
What was that, Morty Jr.?
Were you gonna say Dada?
Say Dada.
Death!
Dada.
Domination!
Dada?
Destruction, domination.
Nice.
The spider in sector C
is still alive.
Plan your route accordingly
and expect delays.
We're not telling you what to do.
We're just sharing how we feel.
And now, weather. Is anyone
else cold or is it just me?
I am Marsha,
ruler of Gazorpazorp.
I am here if you need to talk.
What is this place?
Paradise. We built it during
the great passive aggression,
when females separated
from the males
due to their increasingly
destructive behavior.
- I'm here if you need to talk.
From here we dispense
mechanical surrogates
to maintain our population.
Fertilized surrogates are
returned here to our nursery.
The females are placed
into educational program
where they can discover a
service to our paradise
that fulfills them most.
The males...
they get to play outside.
That was just a baby.
And within a day he'll be
an adult male Gazorpian,
one of the most aggressively
violent creatures in the universe.
Wait a minute.
We're here because a male Gazorpian
was born on our planet.
You speak when you're
spoken to ding-a-ling.
It's true though. One of your
babies was born on earth.
Are you the ruler of this earth?
How did you know?
- The quality of your top.
- Do you love it?
I love it.
I'm here if you need to talk.
- I'm here if you need to talk.
If the Gazorpian is male
your earth is in grave danger.
We will give you passage back home,
so it can be terminated.
But first, mojitos!
We don't have time for mojitos!
You are insulting them.
I don't care Summer.
This place is the worst!
I wanna go home!
Well, it really doesn't matter
what you want
because this is a sane place,
where women rule.
You know what I have
to say about that?
I can not believe... my ears.
Boy, who let the
frogs out, huh?
Grandpa!
- Grandpa?
- That sounds patriarchal.
It means father of fathers.
Then this one is
not your slave
and your earth is yet another
planet dominated by men.
It's not dominated
by us, okay?
On earth men and
women are equals.
Equals? We make 70% of your
salary for the same job!
Seize them!
Was this really the time
to make that point, Summer?
This is for you Daddy.
Oh man.
Okay.
Listen to me Morty Jr.
I gotta tell you
something very important, okay?
Killing is bad.
Bad.
You are silly, Daddy.
No, Morty Jr.
I'm being serious, okay?
You need to put your energy
into something else.
I mean what about dancing?
Would you like to learn how to dance?
I like to dance...
on the graves of my enemies.
No, Morty Jr.!
Daddy, can I go outside?
No, absolutely not!
But that's where all the people
and the animals are.
Yeah, but you can't go
out there because...
The air is poisonous, for you!
You will die if...
You'll die instantly
if you ever leave this house.
Do you hear me?
- For real?
- For real times a million, buddy.
So let's just stay inside...
let's try dancing. Right?
Look at me.
We're gonna dance. Come on.
Join, dance with me here.
We love to dance.
Why do we love to dance?
Because I said so!
- Nice.
So, what are you in for?
Because I got a big...
you know...
penis between my legs.
What are you in for?
The worst crime
a female can commit.
Veronica Ann Bennett, I find you
guilty of having bad bangs.
You ever noticed the ones with bad
bangs always have three names?
You are hereby sentenced to...
the silent treatment!
This is gonna be cake.
No!
Jackie!
Rick and Summer of earth.
For the crimes of treason
against woman kind
and for creating the sound
of which we do not speak
because it does not exist,
you are hereby sentenced to...
What? A night on the couch?
Death.
I hate you so much right now.
This will be the first
instance of capital punishment
in our society in 500 years
due to our awesomeness.
So we are forced to improvise.
We placed a large
boulder on that ledge.
Holly shit! You're gonna
crush us with a boulder?!
No! Stop interrupting!
The boulder falls onto a lever
that will launch...
- Knives.
- What?!
Just give me a gun,
I'll kill myself.
Stop interrupting!
The knives will...
Fine!
You were right the
first time, okay?
The boulder crushes you.
I just didn't want to
admit you were right.
- Happy?!
- Just ignore them.
- Ignore them.
- Such an asshole.
Look, I'm sorry, Summer.
I feel bad that I let you
drag us into this.
I wish could have been
a better grandpa to you.
And you know, for
what it's worth,
that is a really nice cute top,
that you're wearing there.
Top?
My top!
The same top you
complimented earlier.
Look! Look at the tag!
Read it!
It says...
Mark Jacobs.
Mark? Jacob?
These are names of the penis.
Yes.
An earth man made this top.
Maybe on your planet
separation of the genders
is the right thing to do,
but on earth, a certain
percentage of males are born gay,
which is why my clothes
are better than all of yours.
It's true.
And sometimes the truth hurts.
But it must be accepted.
Like if I told you
that you're using
a wrong color foundation
for your skin,
and it ends at your neck
making you look like a party clown.
Okay.
Ouch. Noted.
But the fact remains if you impose
Gazorpazorp's laws on earth
you're no better than the men
whose farts shall remain unspoken
And if you think my top is cute,
you cannot execute.
Very well. Give the earth people
spacecraft
so they may head
back to their weird planet
where women are kind of equal,
but not really.
Good job, Summer,
and thanks girls.
You girls are really...
something, I tell you that.
You know,
when we first got here
- I was like...
- Give them a ship, now.
Morty Jr.! Smoking?!
That is not okay!
What are you gonna
do, ground me?
I can't go outside anyway!
So what? You could
do things inside.
You could play guitar,
you could masturbate...
I don't wanna masturbate,
I wanna conquer the planet!
Oh, here we go again!
Who do you think
is gonna love you
if you conquer the
planet Morty Jr.?
Love.
That's all you care about.
What about weapons? What about
domination of the enemy?
Alright, that's it, no
more History Chanel!
This TV is for cartoons
and video games only!
I hate video games!
You take that back!
Give it to me!
I didn't mean!
I didn't mean that!
I didn't mean to do that!
I'm sorry!
I can't take this anymore!
I'd rather breath poison than
living another minute with you!
No! No, no, no! Stop!
My life has been a lie!
God is dead!
The government's lame!
Thanksgiving is about
killing Indians!
Jesus wasn't born on Christmas,
they moved the date,
it was a pagan holiday!
- Oh, Dad!
- Yes, Morty?
My son is gonna
take over the planet,
and I am too young to drive.
Can you help me get him back?
I suppose, Morty.
I suppose.
But first a deep sip from a very
tall glass of "I told you so".
Oh my god, please Dad,
come on!
Dad, there he is!
Oh God.
Hey stop that!
Oh my god, oh my god, Dad!
Morty Jr., no!
It's me.
It's Dad.
It's okay.
Put the car down Morty Jr.
No!
Where's your hands?
My car!
d And that's how we play
handy hands. d
- Out of the way, Morty!
- No!
Morty, that's one of
the most violently
aggressive creature
in the universe.
He's my son!
And if you hurt him,
you have to kill me, Rick!
Dad, I'm so confused.
I know Morty Jr.
I'm sorry.
I ended up lying to you
and yelling at you
just like my
parents did to me.
You know parents are just
kids having kids.
One minute you like how
a shiny robot looks,
the next minute you're in
a fist fight with your alien son.
I'm an alien?
We all have bad impulses,
bad thoughts.
We just have to learn to channel them
into something constructive.
But I want to murder
everyone I see.
Well you know, maybe there is a job
out there for people that feel that way.
Actually, there is.
Hi, I'm Brad Anderson.
Creator of the nationally syndicated
comic strip "Marmaduke".
You should consider
being a creative.
I'm hunted by
uncontrollable thoughts
of mutilation and sexual assaults
on a nearly daily basis.
But you know? I channeled
it all into my work.
I never got that impression
from reading Marmaduke.
Well, did you get the impression
I was trying to make you laugh?
Tell me that wasn't
Brad Anderson.
See, you hear that, Morty Jr.?
Maybe you could try being
a creative of some kind.
Maybe? I always
have sort of wanted
to see my face on the
back of a novel.
I mean what I really wanna do
is slit people's throat,
but, beyond that.
I know you can do it, son.
I think it's time
I get a place of my own.
I promise I call you every day
I need money
or a place to do laundry.
So, I assume this novel
your son writes
is gonna pay for my rear Axel?
Isn't it interesting Summer,
that after all that stuff we just did
nothing really mattered,
there was no point to it.
Kind of makes you wonder, huh?
- About nothing
- Are you sure it doesn't make
you re-evaluate your policy
about taking girls on adventure?
No I'd say given
what we've been through,
that I was right the whole time,
and any epiphanies
about gender politics were
projection of your feminine insecurity.
But hey, why don't you
have pink spaceship?
Go ride around,
and have a jolly old time.
Maybe that'll shut you up.
Dad? Summer? Where were you
guys this whole time?
On Gazorpazorp.
Where were you?
I was reading a newspaper.
Oh, that's interesting, Beth.
You know it's funny...
I heard about a little bit
of news, myself.
Take a look.
Take a listen.
This world... still got a...
still got a chance!
See you guys next week!
See everybody next week!
Mortimer Smith Jr.
New York Times best selling author.
Your book is about innocence,
the definition of it,
and inevitably
its impossibility.
Is it autobiographical?
Certainly.
I mean,
all writing is, in my opinion.
But, my...
My father...
kept me locked in the house
until I was a teenager.
And there was violence and...
threats of poison gas.
- But also dancing.
- But you persevered
and created this masterpiece
from your suffering.
Smith Jr.'s mind-bending novel,
"My Horrible Father"
in every store
and on everyone's mind pick
it up, we'll be right back.
It's a thankless job, Morty.
You did the best you could.
I hope he's eating enough.
Subtitles by Ozymandias
Corrections by XhmikosR