Sync & corrections by XhmikosR
www.addic7ed.com
Run!
Morty, do it!
Hit the button now!
I can't do it, Rick!
They're my parents and sister!
Morty, I already told
you it's not your family!
They're clones from
an alternate reality,
possessed by demonic alien spirits
from another dimension's future!
Do you need a mnemonic device
or something?
Just hit the button, already!
Morty, please, I love
you, sweetheart.
Oh!
Good work, Morty.
You know, these demonic alien
spirits are really valuable.
You okay, Morty? I told you
not to trust that tuna.
I just killed my family!
I don't care what they were.
I don't know, Morty.
Some people'd pay top dollar for
that kind of breakthrough.
You know what, Rick?
That's it!
I'm done with these insane
adventures!
That was really traumatizing!
- I quit! I'm out!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Come on, Morty, don't
be like that.
The universe is a crazy,
chaotic place.
You're the one that's
crazy and chaotic!
Adventures are supposed to be
simple and fun.
Oh, yeah, Morty, yeah.
Yeah, that that that's real easy to
say from the sidekick position.
But but, uh, how about next time...
you be in charge, and then we'll
talk about how simple and fun it is?
Seriously, Rick?
You'll you'll let me call
the shots?
Okay, yeah, fine.
But let's make it
interesting, Morty.
If your adventure sucks
and we bail halfway through it,
you lose the right to bitch
about all future adventures.
Plus, you have to do my laundry
for a month.
Okay, all right, tough guy!
But if my adventure's good...
I get to be in charge of
every third adventure!
- Every 10th.
- Deal. All right.
Well, come on, let's get going.
Dad, the dishwasher's
doing that thing again.
- Washing dishes?
- No. The opposite.
Can you fix it?
Grandpa Rick, can you help me
with my science homework?
- Yeah just don't do it.
- Grandpa!
Hey, Rick, you got
some kind of hand-shaped device
that can open this
mayonnaise jar?
Wow. Hat trick.
All right, Morty, let's put a
pin in this.
I got to help your
pathetic family.
Oh, that sounds like
something a chicken would say.
Bawk, bawk, bawk,
bawk, bawk, bawk.
Oh, Morty, you done did
it this time.
It's on.
I can't wait to watch your
adventure lay a huge fart.
As for you dingdongs...
This is a Meeseeks box.
Let me show you how it works.
You press this.
I'm Mr. Meeseeks!
Look at me!
You make a request.
Mr. Meeseeks, open Jerry's
stupid mayonnaise jar.
Yes, siree!
The Meeseeks fulfills
the request.
- All done!
- Wow!
And then it stops existing.
- Oh, my God, he exploded!
- Trust me, they're fine with it.
Knock yourselves out just
keep your requests simple.
They're not gods.
All right!
Get out of here now!
Everybody out of here!
I got a bet to win!
- So many possibilities.
- My mind is racing.
If we're gonna use this thing,
which I'm not even sure we should,
we need to keep it simple.
- I'm Mr. Meeseeks!
- I want to be popular at school!
- Ooh, okay!
- Summer, what did I just-
Ooh, I'm Mr. Meeseeks!
Look at me!
I want I want to
be a more complete woman!
- Beth!
- Oh, yeah! Yes, ma'am!
You guys are doing it wrong.
He said "simple."
Hey, there. I'm Mr. Meeseeks!
Mr. Meeseeks, I would like to take
two strokes off my golf game.
Ooh, yeah! Can do!
Nailed it.
God, Morty, what a
boring start to an adventure.
Why didn't we
just go to Kentucky?
Rick, this is a fantasy-type world with
creatures and all sorts of fantasy things.
- We're going on a quest, okay?
- Can't wait.
Ahem. Excuse me!
We are two humble heroes
in search of adventure!
Oh, my God, so embarrassing.
At last! Two heroes!
You must help us!
This village is terribly poor,
yet the giant that lives in the
clouds above has untold treasures!
You know what?
I accept your call to
adventure, good sir, kind sir.
Come on, Rick.
- There's a giant in the clouds!
- Yeah.
Beginner's luck.
In conclusion, a friendship
with Summer Smith is the most
valuable and enriching
experience of your young lives.
I'm Mr. Meeseeks!
Look at me!
Thank you!
Uh, Mr. Meeseeks, was it?
Yeah. Gene Vagina.
Listen, I'm in a bit of custody
thing with my ex and was wondering-
No, I'll get your info
from Summer.
I got pregnant at 17.
I mean, I still put myself
through veterinary school.
Yes, I'm successful, but what if
I hadn't...
I'm just saying,
somewhere along the way,
I lost that wide-eyed
girl from muskegon.
She's still there, Beth.
Well, her waistline isn't.
Beth, having a family doesn't mean
that you stop being an individual.
You know the best thing you can
do for people that depend on you?
Be honest with them, even if it
means setting them free.
You're saying I should
leave Jerry.
I can't believe I'm finally
having this conversation.
More wine?
I think I've had enough.
Remember to square
your shoulders, Jerry.
Yeah, yeah. I got it.
That's okay.
I'm Mr. Meeseeks! Look at me!
Try again and keep your head
down.
Okay, well, which is it?
Square my shoulders or keep my
head down?
Well, it's both.
But most importantly,
you got to relax.
You know what, Mr. Meeseeks?
I don't think this is working.
I give up.
I'm sorry, Jerry, but it
doesn't work like that.
I'm Mr. Meeseeks.
I have to fulfill my purpose so
I can go away.
Look at me.
Well, make yourself
comfortable, because I suck.
No, Jerry, I'm the
one who sucks!
Let me try something.
I'm Mr. Meeseeks!
Look at me!
Hi, Mr. Meeseeks!
- I'm Mr. Meeseeks! Look at me.
- Hi!
Can you help me get two strokes
off of Jerry's golf swing?
Can do!
I'm Mr. Meeseeks!
Is he keeping his shoulders
squared?
Ooh, he's trying!
All right, Morty.
We're in your stupid
giant's castle.
What do we do next?
Would you just relax, Rick?
All we got to do is find the
treasure room, okay?
It's nice and simple.
You know, I'm sorry everything's
going so smoothly and adventurously.
Uh-oh, Morty.
Startin' to get a little hairy.
What do you want to do, boss?
Come on, hurry.
Behind this cookie jar.
Fee! Fi! Fo! Fum!
Just give up, Morty.
This is game over.
I'll take us home right now.
You just say the word.
No way, Rick.
This is all part of it.
Adventures have conflict.
Deal with it.
I smell the blood of-
whoop!
- Holy crap.
- Oh, boy.
He looks pretty bad down there,
Morty.
Looks like he's bleeding out.
Oh, Jesus! Dale!
You sons of bitches!
Oh, man.
Hello, 911?
My husband has been attacked
by tiny people! He's dying!
Hey, look, we get it.
You're little, you're down on your
luck, you think, "hey, he's a giant.
Why don't we break into his
home, rob him, and murder him?"
Th-th but that's not
how it went down!
Oh, well, it's going down
like that.
You're both going down like
that.
Ooh, boy, Morty, you're
really showing me how it's done.
Real straightforward and fun.
Like, letting go of the need
to be popular is what
makes people like you.
The most important love you
can receive is from yourself.
Okay, Jerry, you got to just
choke up on the club!
Well, which is it,
choke up or follow-through?!
Aww, come on, Jerry, we've
been over this.
You know you got to do both!
This is as frustrating for us
as it is for you.
Don't tell me that!
That just puts pressure on me!
- Just try to relax.
- You try to relax!
Have you ever tried to relax?!
It is a paradox!
Ugh, these Meeseeks, huh?
Kind of a handful.
I can't imagine what you two
must be going through.
Our Meeseeks have been
gone for hours, Jerry.
You're kidding me.
Notice anything different?
I'm sorry. Hours?
Dad, mom is a beautiful woman!
Look at her!
You will lose her!
Uhh...
Hey, Jerry, you mind if we
get back to the task at hand?
Meeseeks don't usually have to
exist this long.
It's getting weird.
Order in the court!
Before the jury
reaches its verdict,
I just want to say that
I consider you both very guilty.
Oh, great adventure, buddy. Rick
and Morty go to giant prison.
You know, if somebody
drops the soap,
it's gonna land on our heads
and crush our spines, Morty.
You know, it'll be really
easy to rape us after that.
- We're gonna be okay, Rick.
- How?
They took my portal gun.
This is an open-and-shut case,
Morty.
You know, what do you
think's gonna happen,
some magical angel's
gonna show up and then-
Fee! Fi! Fo! Fum!
I smell the violation
of civil liberties!
Your honor, I'm from a
tiny-persons advocacy group
and I have here in my
hand a motion to dismiss.
These little men were never
read their giant rights
and are therefore
free-fi to fo-home.
W-what the hell is he
talking about?
They're free to go, is what I
meant.
I'm deconstructing our
our our thing we say.
We're giants. Nobody got that?
Whatever.
Oh, man, what did I
tell you, Rick?
We did it!
All right, Morty, looks like the
portal gun's still working.
You ready to head home?
Oh, yeah, you'd like
that, wouldn't you, Rick?
Well, you know what?
We're not bailing out just yet.
You know, we're gonna go find
some treasure or something
and and we're gonna bring it
to those villagers.
Morty, cut your losses.
This is obviously a wash.
Yeah, you were saying
that back when we first got arrested,
but here we are, you know, walking
down the courthouse steps.
Oh, boy, Morty.
Usually, walking
down the courthouse steps
is the easy part
of the adventure.
What do you say, Morty?
I say give me a hand, sidekick.
Everybody shut up!
Let me try!
Damn it! Damn it! Damn it!
I'm going out.
Wait. What?
Well, you're busy.
I'm hungry.
I thought I'd go out.
Do you want me to be happy or do
you want me to be in prison?
Whoa, whoa, where in the hell is
I'll take you to dinner.
Hey, you know what?
It's hard being me, too.
I'll be right there.
Look, I've got a
marriage to keep together.
At this point, my golf swing is
more your problem than mine.
I can't take it anymore.
I just want to die!
We all want to die!
We're Meeseeks!
Why did you even
rope me into this?
'Cause he roped me into this!
Well, him over there, he
roped me into this!
Well, he roped me into this!
Well, what about me?
He roped me into this.
Well, that one over there
roped me into this.
Well, he roped me into this.
Yeah, Morty, this is
the part of the story everybody loves
scaling down 650,000
oversized steps.
All right, okay,
you know, if this was a story,
this part wouldn't
be included, stupid.
Hey, Rick, what do you know?
Look down there.
Looks like some kind
of tavern or something
built right into
the side of the step.
Oh, wow, Rick.
Now, this is more like it.
Look, there's little
staircase-shaped people in here.
All kinds of crazy characters.
This place is great, you know?
It's whimsical and fun.
What are you looking at, mother-
Easy, Rick.
Pay them no mind.
Those stair goblins
can be moody.
Now, what can I getcha?
We've got skarlog poppies,
flurlow, halzingers, bloogies,
juicy time babies.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, how
about some scotch whiskey?
You got any of that around here?
Or just a bunch of nonsense
words?
Rick...
We'll have two bloogies, please.
And, uh, we were wondering,
is there a faster way two heroes
could get down these stairs?
Y'all need to ride
down the stairs?
My name is
slippely-slippery stair.
I'll take you down there for
25 shmeckels.
25 shmeckels?
I don't know how much I
don't know what that is.
Is that a lot? Is it a little?
That's exactly how much I
spent on my big fake boobies.
Hi, I'm Mr. booby buyer.
I'll buy those boobies for
25 shmeckels.
It's a tempting offer, but
I'm gonna have to decline.
Rats! What a shame.
Morty, your adventure's
in a spiral.
For real, man, time to pull out.
You keep heckling my
adventure, Rick!
- You know why?
- Uh, because it's lame?
It's because you're petty!
You know, how many
times have I had
to follow you into some
nonsensical bull crap?
I always roll with the punches,
Rick.
Why can't you?
Look, I got to take a leak, and
when I come back,
if you haven't learned how to
lighten up, don't be here!
Whatever.
It's become clear-look at me-
that if we concentrate all
our efforts on Jerry's follow-through,
we will solve this problem.
- I'm Mr. Meeseeks.
- I'm Mr. Meeseeks. Look at me.
The only thing that's clear
is that choking up is
the one true solution.
Look at me. I'm Mr. Meeseeks.
I've been trying to help
Jerry for two days,
an eternity in Meeseeks time,
and nothing's worked.
I fear the worst.
Your failures are your own,
old man.
I'm Mr. Meeseeks! Look at me.
I say follow-through!
Who's with me?!
Follow-through!
I'm Mr. Meeseeks! Look at me!
Kill him!
How are you today?
- I'm Mr. jelly bean.
- Hi, Mr. jelly bean.
I'm Morty.
My grandpa and I are on an
adventure.
- Nice. Is it a fun adventure?
- I hope so.
But I'm starting to get nervous
that maybe it's gone a little
too far off the rails.
Isn't that what adventures do?
Hey, you know what?
You're right.
Everything's going fine.
I just got to relax and go with
the flow.
Yeah.
Okay. Uh. B-bye.
Uhh, no, stay.
Go with the flow.
Stop.
You're making me really
uncomfortable.
Stop fighting me.
Just let this happen.
Get off of me!
d Sweet home Alabama d
Whoo!
No! Stop! Please!
Stop being such a
tease, you sweet little-
No! No!
Everybody sto-o-o-p!
Look at me!
My brothers, nothing will be
accomplished by shedding
Meeseeks blood.
None of us can die until our job
is done.
The job can't be done!
We'll never get two strokes off
his game!
No, we won't.
But we will get all strokes off
his game.
Where's he going with this?
What's he mean?
When we kill him.
Jerry, maybe it's time I take
that trip I always talk about.
Where would you go?
I don't know, man.
Italy. Greece. Argentina.
Countries known for their
sexually aggressive men.
Did I tell you how much I
love your new haircut?
What the heck?
There he is!
Run, Jerry!
Come on out, Jerry!
Guys, I'll choke up.
I'll follow through.
I'll do whatever you tell me to
do, okay?
Oh, we're well past that, Jerry.
Come on, Rick, quit stalling.
What do ya got?
Read 'em and weep, fellas!
Oh, hey, Morty.
Listen, I'm really sorry about
all that stuff I said earlier
about your adventure.
I'm havin' a good time, Morty.
- It's not so bad.
- Let's just go home, okay?
I'm calling it.
The adventure's over.
We can't leave now, Morty.
- I'm on fire!
- Look, I want to leave now.
You win the bet, okay?
Just give me the portal gun and
let's go, please.
Please, I just want to go home.
Okay.
Listen, Morty.
I just won a bunch of shmeckels.
Why don't we use 25 of them
to pay slippery stair here for a
ride back to the village,
and then we'll give the rest of the
shmeckels to the villagers, huh?
- Really?
- Sure, Morty. Yeah.
You know, a good adventure needs
a good ending.
Buckle up!
Meeseeks are not born into this
world fumbling for meaning, Jerry!
We are created to serve
a singular purpose for which we will
go to any lengths to fulfill!
Existence is pain to a Meeseeks,
Jerry.
And we will do anything to
alleviate that pain.
Just ask...
Aah!
...what's your name, ma'am?
Samantha. Please, mister!
Give him what he wants!
Innocent people are
going to die because of me.
Why am I so mediocre?
Jerry, turn around.
Straighten your back.
Bend your knees.
Bend them.
Square your shoulders.
Take a deep breath.
I love you.
I'm counting to three, Jerry.
What the is going on?
He's got it!
That's a lower handicap
stro-o-ke!
Excuse me.
I'm a bit of a stickler
Meeseeks.
What about your short game?
Oh, my God, oh, my God!
What about your short game?!
Ooh, nice!
I think we'll take our
food to go.
No, you won't.
The police are coming.
You have so many questions to
answer.
Fair enough.
Thank you, kind sir.
Our village is saved!
You are both true heroes!
Good job, Morty.
Looks like you won the bet.
Thanks, Rick, but I
don't know if I should.
You know, you were right about
the universe.
It's a crazy and chaotic place.
Well, you know, maybe
that's why it could use a little
cleaning up every now
and then, you know.
This one's wrapped up neat and clean
because we did it Morty style.
Oh! Heroes, we would like to
introduce you to our beloved king
so that he may thank you
personally.
Uh, no, I-it's cool.
Rick. Portal. Hurry.
So...
You still thinking about taking
that trip?
Jerry, look.
We don't have a perfect marriage,
but I'm not going anywhere.
When we were in that freezer,
I realized the Meeseeks are like
the guys I went to high school with
willing to say anything
to "complete their task."
Was I one of those guys?
The difference is you
didn't disappear afterwards.
Well...
I got you pregnant.
Yeah...
What the hell happened
to this place?
Uh, your Meeseeks box happened.
They went crazy when
they couldn't take
two strokes off
Jerry's golf game.
He felt terrible.
Hey, it's not my fault
that Jerry's an idiot.
Dad!
Is there anything you can do to
clean this place up?
Well, you know, I do
have a Fleeseeks box.
No. No more boxes.
What?
It just has a mop and some floor
wax in it.
Wubba lubba dub dubs!
Yeah! That's my new thing!
I'm kind of like what's his
name Arsenio.
Isn't that it's what Arsenio
used to say on his show.
Wobble gobba lop bops!
Right?
See you next week, everybody.
I don't get it.
Sir, I think you're going to
want to see this.
We found it inside a lockbox
inside king jelly bean's closet.
We have to tell the people.
Wait.
Destroy it.
Our people will get more from
the idea he represented...
than from the jelly bean
he actually was.
Sync & corrections by XhmikosR
www.addic7ed.com