Hey, Rick. I have to make a project
for the science fair this weekend.
- You think you could help me out?
- Whatever.
Well, I mean, traditionally, science
fairs are a father-son thing.
Well, scientifically,
traditions are an idiot thing.
Morty, I think it would
be fun for you to work on a
science project with your dad.
Uh...
Yeah, dad.
Why don't we do it together?
Yes!
You backed the right horse on
this one, son.
We'll get out the crayons,
brew some coffee,
and knock this thing out
in two or three days.
- What is my purpose?
- Pass the butter.
Thank you.
Dad, I need a ride to work.
Maybe Rick can give
you a ride.
I'm helping Morty with science.
I'm busy.
Doing what?
Uh, anything else.
- What is my purpose?
- You pass butter.
Oh, my god.
Yeah, welcome to
the club, pal.
Corrections by XhmikosR
www.addic7ed.com
- Since when do you have a job?
- Since last week.
It's part-time at this little
vintage thrift store.
My boss is this really smart,
eccentric old man that treats me
nice and values me.
Meow.
Can't wait to meet this
fascinating character.
Please don't.
Oh.
Well, when did this stop being
Jamba Juice?
I've just recently opened for
business, mister, um, Goldenfold.
You know my name?
That's disarming.
I also know you long for
female company.
You know, it has been lonely
since the divorce.
Some voids can't be filled with
Jamba Juice.
This aftershave makes a man
quite irresistible to women.
Free of charge.
One never pays here--
not with money.
Nothing to read into there.
Thanks!
Sorry I'm late, mr. Needful.
This is my grandpa, Rick.
He was just leaving.
Huh.
Tell me, Rick, what
do you desire?
Eh, I make my own stuff.
So, what are you--
like, the devil?
- What? Sorry?
- I don't know.
Store comes out of nowhere, all
the shit's old and creepy.
Are you the devil? A demon?
- Leprechaun?
- Grandpa Rick!
Hey, I'm not judging.
Just like shoot straight.
I'm a man of science.
Ah, then perhaps you could
make use of this.
This microscope reveals things
beyond comprehension.
Grandpa, go home and drink.
Why don't we do a
model of the solar system?
That's what my dad did with me
when I was your age.
Oh, okay.
You know, Rick's in
his lab, making cyborgs and
wormholes and all that weird
stuff, but this is real science.
A man and his boy,
making planets.
Hey, how about we use a
ping-pong ball for Pluto?
And then Jupiter --
Uh, actually, I don't
think Pluto's a planet.
Of course Pluto's a planet, son.
I learned that in
the third grade.
Well, yeah, but you
know they changed it.
Morty, nobody changed
the planets.
I just googled it.
Pluto's not a planet.
They changed it in 2006.
Yeah, I heard about
that, Morty.
- And I disagree.
- You disagree?
That's right.
It's possible to disagree in
science, Morty.
Pluto was a planet.
Some committee of fancy assholes
disagree.
I disagree back.
Give me a ping-pong ball.
Um, okay.
I-I just have to...
Go find Rick and
go over my head about Pluto?
No.
Geez, I just got to go to the
bathroom.
Damn.
Oh.
Okay, good.
This is gonna be fun.
Hey, Morty, let me ask you
a question real quick.
Does evil exist, and if so, can
one detect and measure it?
Um...
Rhetorical question, Morty.
The answer's "yes, you just have
to be a genius".
Cute.
Your sister's boss
gave me a microscope
that would have made
me retarded.
Ooh.
Oh, boy, Rick.
I'm don't think you're allowed
to say that word, you know?
Morty, I'm not disparaging
the differently abled.
I'm stating the fact that if I
had used this microscope,
it would have made me
mentally retarded.
Okay, yeah, but I don't think
it's about logic, Rick.
I think the word has just become
a symbolic issue for powerful
groups that feel like they're
doing the right thing.
Well, that's retarded.
What are you guys
talking about?
Apparently, nothing.
You asked him if
Pluto's a planet, didn't you?
- No!
- It's not.
- Shut up, Rick.
- Whoa.
I don't care what anyone says.
If it can be a planet,
it can be a planet again.
Planet.
Planet, planet, planet.
Stay scientific, Jerry.
This aftershave made women want
me, but it also made me impotent!
A price for everything,
mr. Goldenfold.
A price for everything.
Oh, my God!
How could I not see this
coming?!
My lust!
My greed!
I deserved this!
This serum should counteract
the negative effects.
Holy cats!
Ladies, let's get out of here.
I haven't learned a thing!
Here.
You can have this back.
You didn't use it?
Sure I did -- to develop this.
It detects and catalogs all your
"twilight zone", "ray bradbury",
"Friday the 13th" the series
voodoo crap magic.
I thought you might want it so
you didn't accidentally sell
anybody, say...
A typewriter that generates
best-selling murder mysteries
and then makes the murders
happen in real life?
- Ooh.
- Be quiet.
Don't you want to make sure people
know what they're getting?
You're not intentionally
selling...
beauty cream that makes ugly ladies
pretty but also makes them blind?
I find this all quite
preposterous.
Oh, I say, good sir.
Oh, harrumph.
Oh, oh
Oh, oh that's beautiful.
You know it's gonna be wearing
you in three hours?
Do I need to call the police?
Here, you can use my phone.
Don't worry. It won't make you
deaf because I'm not a hack.
You think you're so great,
you stupid piece of shit.
Stop! Hey!
[Beep] you, man.
Stop it right now!
Grandpa Rick, I like working
here.
You work for the devil.
So what?
"So what?"
Yes, so what if he's
the devil, Rick?
At least the devil has a job.
At least he's active in the
community.
What do you do?
You eat our food and make
gadgets.
Buh-bye.
Whoops.
I'm sorry, mr. Needful.
I'll clean that up.
I don't know what I can do about
the ghost lady that came out of
it, but --
It's fine.
Summer, you know, your
grandfather's right.
This store curses people.
That's my business.
Well, yeah.
Fast-food gives people diabetes,
and clothing stores have
sweatshops.
Is there a company hiring
teenagers that isn't evil?
This is my first job.
You've been nice to me,
mr. Needful.
You respect me.
Please, call me "the devil".
I'd rather not, actually.
Yes, perhaps not during
business hours.
I told you, I want to file a
declaration that Pluto is a planet.
Well, then my son's going to
fail his science class,
and when that happens,
I'm suing you first.
I think I know what the "a" in
NASA stands for.
Dad, what's your endgame?
Ain't no game, sucka.
Why don't we just make the solar
system with eight planets?
It's even easier.
Sure, sure, and why
don't we just burn Galileo at
the stake for saying
the sun is round?
Science isn't always easy,
Morty.
- Whoa!
What the hell?!
I'm king Flippy Nips,
ruler of Pluto.
We discovered you quite by
accident during routine
surveillance of your world.
You really gave it to those guys
at NASA.
I was -- you know,
sometimes science is about
conviction.
I'd like to introduce you to
a few people that very much
agree with you.
Oh, I...
Plutonians.
Jerry Smith is a
scientist from earth,
where he's creating a
model of our solar system.
Jerry, tell Pluto about your
decision.
Um... Pluto's a planet.
Pluto's a [beep] planet, bitch!
Oh, man.
This is definitely gonna go to
his head.
If it's athletic prowess you desire,
principle vagina, I might --
- I'll take it.
- But I haven't even --
Thank you very, very much.
Great store. Great place. Bye.
Huh. Okay.
I must say, summer, I thought
your grandfather's outburst
would have disrupted business,
but this is the best weekend
I've had since salem.
Nice.
- "Wholesome delight" for lunch?
- Is that the vegan place?
- Yeah, I love their soup.
- I'm kind of soup-ed out.
Mrs. Tate, is it?
What do you desire?
Whoa, whoa, slow down, honey.
Oh, is there a limit?
Everything's free, right?
Let's just say you
don't pay... with money.
That was perfect.
You pay with the
curses, right?
Um... I -- well...
But, mrs. Tate, why do you want
cursed items?
Well, I'm going to get the curses
removed at "Curse Purge Plus".
You know, the guy on TV?
What?
Have you acquired
creepy specific old stuff from
a mysterious antique or thrift
store that gives you powers but
[beep] with you in
unforeseeable ways?
Bring it to "Curse Purge Plus".
I use science to
un-curse the items for cash,
and you get to
keep the powers.
This guy got mysterious
sneakers to make him run
faster, but guess what?
He would have had to run until
he died, making them worthless.
I removed the curse, making
them worth, like, I don't know,
$8 million.
See you at the olympics.
This eerily intelligent doll was
threatening to murder its family.
Now it does their taxes.
Everything's deductible.
Don't pay for cool
stuff with your soul.
Pay for it with money.
You know, like how every other
store in the world works?
We're located at First and Main
in old town.
Come on -- come on down.
"First and..."
That's right across the street
from "Needful Things," where you
can get evil items for free!
Diabolic son of a motherf--
We're back on
"Good morning, Pluto."
And a very good morning it is
for our guest,
earth scientist Jerry Smith, who's
making headlines with his bold
announcement that is what,
Jerry?
Pluto is a planet.
- Well, how about that.
- I love it.
Morty Smith.
I'm Scroopy Noopers.
I'm a scientist.
- Can I show you something?
- Uh, I better not.
Right now.
The center of Pluto, mr. Smith,
is made of a substance called
"Plutonium".
Mines like these suck Plutonium
up to the cities,
where corporations use
it to power everything,
from diamond cars to
golden showers.
And the more we remove,
the more Pluto shrinks.
There it goes again.
Just shrank a little.
But a few years ago, your
scientists noticed Pluto had
gotten so small they couldn't
even call it a "planet" anymore.
Should've been our wake-up call.
But the rich Plutonians
won't wake up,
and they love your dad
telling everyone Pluto's a
planet because that means they
can keep mining until Pluto goes
from planet to asteroid to
meteor, and finally...
Um, a party?
Is everyone in your family
an idiot?
Well, for sure me and
my dad are.
Well, all you have to do
is get him to admit that,
and you could save
four billion lives.
Yeah, you know, the thing is
my dad's really insecure.
Hmm. Funny.
Mr. Needful, out of
everything in the store,
you'll never guess
what we couldn't get rid of.
Oh, my god.
I wish this desk was lighter.
I wish this knot was looser.
Come on.
I don't --
Wait, what am I doing?
I wish I knew CPR.
1, 2, 3.
Oh, Jesus.
What a waste of a monkey paw.
Mr. Needful, how could you even think
of doing something so horrible?
I'm the devil.
What should I do when I
fail -- get myself an ice cream?
You haven't failed.
People like Rick are making
me obsolete.
I mean, seriously.
I may be "the devil",
but your grandpa is the devil.
I just want to go back to hell,
where everyone thinks
I'm smart and funny.
No!
It's not fair.
Everyone in this town got something
they wanted from you -- even Rick.
I was your only friend,
and I get nothing?
Okay.
I'll give you one thing.
- Name it.
- I want to help you.
Clever twist.
I learned from the
best, you old fart.
Now, let's go get
you hydrated.
Looks like we've
got... haunted boxing gloves that
will make you the heavyweight
champion in 1936, and
then you'll be trapped
there, winning the same
fight for eternity.
I can take out the "eternity"
and the padding,
and then you'll have some
time-traveling mittens.
Oh, look, it's Rosemary's baby.
- How's business?
- Here's the last of our inventory.
We're going to file chapter 11
and do some restructuring.
Sounds like code for
"you win, Rick."
That was important to
you, wasn't it?
Nope.
It was important to your dumb
devil friend.
To me, this was all just a bit,
like when bugs bunny [beep] with
the opera singer for 20 minutes.
He tried to kill himself.
Seriously?
Holy crap.
But you know what,
grandpa Rick?
He's strong, and he's never
going to give up.
Uh-huh, yeah, I don't care.
Oh, I know.
Everyone knows you don't care.
So?
So have fun not caring.
- I always do.
- Good.
Yeah, it is good.
It's the best.
I'm sure it is.
- Bye.
- Later.
I'm here to pick up my
undead cat and child.
Yeah, uh... Give me a sec.
These are the forms for the
employee health plan.
All right, yeah, put --
put them on my... Eh.
I just got bored.
Everybody out.
All right, just
one more rally,
then I promise we'll get back
to your science project.
Dad, Pluto isn't a planet.
It's shrinking because of
corporations.
Yeah, that's what that
anti-planet nut job
Scroopy Noopers was screaming
about outside the
ministry of money's fundraiser.
Are you telling me four billion
Plutonians are wrong?
You said science wasn't easy.
I said science isn't
always easy.
Obviously, that means
sometimes it is easy.
Let's not debase ourselves with
word games, son.
Dad, their whole
planet is dying.
Ha!
You called it a planet.
Checkmate.
What's up, Pluto?
Mr. Smith, please tell my friend
here what you just told me.
Go on.
My very eager mother
just served us nine pickles,
and the "pickles" is Pluto.
My god, the man's a genius.
Um, excuse me.
Morty, what?
Dad, what did you
think about the recent report
published by the Pluto science reader
linking Pluto-quakes, sinkholes,
and surface shrinkage to
deep-core Plutonium drilling?
Well, son, what did
you think when you were 5
and you pooped your pants, and you
threw your poopy undies
out your bedroom window because
you thought it was
like throwing something
in the garbage?
I mean, I'm trimming
the hedges,
and these things are just
hanging there.
Was I supposed to think the poop
bunny left them?
Good one, dad.
Hey, Morty, you want to
go on a... Oh.
Hey, Beth.
Hello?
Hey, Jerry, you in here being
stupid?
Thanks.
Hey, you know, I was thinking,
you know, I might watch a movie.
I am not programmed for
friendship.
Suit yourself.
Hey. Hey.
W-w-what's going on?
Um, listen, can you help me do
the stupid science fair project?
Whatever.
Jerry, you must be so excited.
The Pluto-bel prize is the highest
honor a scientist can receive.
I'm flattered and humbled.
Oh, I like that.
Use that in your speech.
Also, talk about Pluto
being a planet.
People like that.
Your highness, we've captured
Scroopy Noopers.
You animals! Animals!
Ooh, look who's little
journey's come to an end.
Take him to Pluto-namo bay.
You can't kill the truth,
father.
What?
I can see you're confused.
Pluto-namo bay is a military prison--
a sort of play on words.
Did he call you "father"?
Scroopy Noopers, the anti-planet
nut job, is your son?
The young eat the old if you
let them, Jerry.
Pluto is a cold, cold
celestial dwarf.
It's a what?
Huh? Oh, planet.
"Pluto is a cold,
cold planet".
That's what I meant.
Knock them dead
out there, you.
Pluto is...
...Not a planet.
Ow!
It's not a planet.
Hey!
It's not a planet!
I'm an idiot,
and I love my son.
It was a long six hours, but
we've overhauled
"Needful Things"
into the globally-compliant
web 4.0,
"e-nomenon", "n33dful.com", spelled
with threes instead of "e"'s.
- Whoo, yeah!
- Whoo, excited!
Okay, that's it.
We just got bought by Google!
Mm.
I'm so proud of you, Lucius.
So, how much did we make?
"We".
This is my business.
Security!
You're Zuckerberg-ing me?
I was Zuckerberg-ing people before
Zuckerberg's balls dropped.
I'm the devil, bitch!
What, what?!
Hey!
- Hey, Morty.
- Oh, oh, hey, dad.
Um, what -- what are you doing
back from Pluto so quick?
Uh... Some people just
can't handle the truth.
Especially dummies like me.
Morty, I'm not as smart as your
grandpa Rick, but
I promise never to make
that your problem again.
Hey, dad.
Nobody's smarter than Rick,
but nobody else is my dad.
You're a genius at that.
Wow.
That's... humbling and
flattering, son.
Thank you.
What say we finish ourselves an
eight-planet solar system?
Um... I'm just gonna take
this thing in and get an "A".
Butter.
But...
You're a genius at
being my dad, dad.
Quit while you're ahead.
And also, knock next time,
you know?
I mean, I'm sitting
in here, I'm 14 --
I got a computer
in here, you know?
Oh, I -- I think I understand.
You're really playing with fire when
you burst in here like that, man.
I get it. Say no more.
I mean, one of these days,
you know, you're gonna end
up seeing something.
I got it!
Noted. Good night.
How's your pretend
grandpa doing, aka "the devil"?
He dumped me.
Oof. Sorry.
Did we learn a lesson
here I'm not seeing?
Not sure.
Maybe in a much bigger way,
mr. Needful gave us
both what we really wanted?
Because I was always jealous of
you hanging out with Morty,
and you didn't realize how
much you valued my approval?
- No, that's dumb.
- Yeah, not satisfying.
I'll tell you what, though.
If -- if -- if it's satisfaction
you're after, I think I might
have an idea.
Uh-huh.
Uh-huh, totally. Let's do it.
d X gonna give it to ya
what? d
d Wait for you to
get it on your own, d
d X gonna deliver to ya d
d knock knock, open up the
door, it's real d
d with the non-stop pop pop and
stainless steel d
d go hard, getting
busy with it d
d but I got such a good heart d
d that I'll make the mother wonder
if he did it d
d damn right, and
I'll do it again, d
d 'cause I am right
so I gots to win d
d break bread with the enemy d
d but no matter how
many cats I break bread with d
d I'll break who you -- d
And that's how I
took my storefront
into the forefront
of the up front.
Thank you, Seattle.
Rick? Summer?
Stupid mother [beep].
You stupid bitch.
How do you like that?
W-w-why?
Because sometimes
what you really need is for
someone else to pay
a horrible price.
- We did it.
- Yeah, bro.
We totally worked it.
- Yeah.
- We just pulled it off.
Yeah, bro.
Yeah.
d Bitch, please, if the only thing
you cats did was came out to play d
d stay out my way, mother-- d
d first we gonna rock,
then we gonna roll d
d then we let it pop,
don't let it go d
d X gonna give it to ya,
he gonna give it to ya d
d first we gonna rock,
then we gonna roll d
d then we let it pop,
don't let it go d
d X gonna give it to ya,
he gonna give it to ya d
d ain't never gave
nothing to me d
Corrections by XhmikosR
www.addic7ed.com