Sync & corrections by XhmikosR
www.addic7ed.com
Principal vagina here.
Don't let the name fool you.
I'm very much in charge
reminding you that tonight
is our annual flu season dance.
I don't know how many
times I have to say this,
but if you have
the flu, stay home.
Hey.
The flu season dance is about
awareness, not celebration.
You don't bring dead babies
to passover.
Okay. Here we go.
Hey, Jessica.
Uh...
What's up, Morty?
What are you doing?
Um...
Wait, wait.
Were you about to talk... to her?
Well... I mean, I was
thinking about it.
Dude, stay in your league.
Look at how hot she is.
You don't see me going to a
bigger school in a wealthier district
and hitting on their
prettiest girl.
Gee, thanks, Brad.
I throw balls far.
You want good words?
Date a languager.
Try not to worry about
it, Morty.
You're a good kid, and there's
not a premium on that right now,
but you'll be getting girls
sometime after Brad's out of shape.
You're missing the point, dad.
I don't want girls.
I want Jessica.
Ah, well, I remember
feeling that way about a young
lady named "your mom," and
that's not an urban diss.
Your mom was my Jessica.
I remember the first time I saw
her.
I thought,
"I should get her pregnant, and
then she'll have to marry me."
I beg your pardon,
Rick. Inappropriate.
Sorry, please proceed
with your story
about banging my
daughter in high school.
I'm not sure you want to take
romantic advice from this guy, Morty.
His marriage is hanging from a
thread.
My marriage is fine, thank you.
Jerry, it's your
house whatever you say it is
is how it is but I think a
blind man could see that Beth is
looking for the door.
I barely have a reason to care,
and even inoticed.
Come on, Rick!
Don't talk about my parents like
that.
Listen, Morty, I hate to break it
to you, but what people call "love"...
is just a chemical reaction
that compels animals to breed.
It hits hard, Morty, then it
slowly fades,
leaving you stranded
in a failing marriage.
I did it.
Your parents are gonna do it.
Break the cycle, Morty.
Rise above. Focus on science.
All right, well, I'm gonna go
get dressed for the dance.
Yeah, I'm just going
to... check on your mom.
Morty, hand me that
screwdriver, huh?
I'm almost finished making my
ionic defibulizer, Morty.
It's gonna be great.
Hey, listen, Rick.
You know how you said that,
you know, love is a chemical and
all that stuff from earlier?
Well, I was thinking, you know,
could you make some
sort of chemical thing
happen inside of Jessica's
mind, you know,
so where she falls in love with me
and all that sort of thing?
You know, like, maybe make some
sort of love potion or
something?
Morty, that's such a
poor use of my time.
It's beneath me.
Hand me the screwdriver.
You know what?
No, Rick!
I'm not gonna hand you the
screwdriver.
I'm not gonna hand you
anything ever again, Rick!
I'm always helping you with this
and that and the other thing.
What about me, Rick?
Why can't you just help
me out once once for once?
You're growing up fast, Morty.
You're growing into a real big
thorn straight up into my ass.
Listen, this is called oxytocin.
I extracted it from a vole.
Do you know what a vole is,
Morty?
You know what a vole is?
It's a it's a rodent that
mates for life, Morty.
This is the chemical released
in a mammal's brain,
you know, that
makes it fall in love.
All right, Morty, I just got to
combine it with some of your DNA.
Oh, well, okay.
A hair, Morty.
I need one of your hairs.
- This isn't "game of thrones."
- Ow!
All right, Morty.
Whoever you smear this stuff on
will fall in love with you,
and only you, forever.
- Are you happy now, Morty?
- Heck, yeah!
Thank you, grandpa Rick.
Hey, there's no... dangers or
anything, or side effects, right?
What am I, a hack?
Go nuts, Morty. It's foolproof.
Eh, unless she has the flu.
- Beth, do you still love me?
- Ugh, what kind of question is that?
The "yes or no" kind?
Jerry, do you want
homeless people to have homes?
- Yes.
- Are you gonna build them?
- No.
- Then what good was the "yes"?
Wait, is loving me the house
or the homeless people?
Loving you is work,
Jerry hard work,
like building a homeless shelter
nobody wants to say no to doing it,
but some people put the work in.
So, what do you say?
Do you see me working here?
Does this conversation seem
tedious to me?
Sort of.
Then I obviously sort
of love you, don't I?
So stop asking, and maybe I'll
love you more.
Crap, they need me at the horse
hospital.
This late?
The racetrack had a
starlight derby.
There was a seven-horse collision,
and Davin's there alone.
Davin.
Davin! Davin.
Davin! Davin!
d Flu, yo d
d you got to be aware d
d aware of all the flu d
d up in the air d
d I'm-a get me a shot d
d and make the flu go away d
d flu-hating rapper d
d just rapping away d
d yo, yo, flu-hating rapper d
d it's a flu-hating rapper d
Hey, there, Jessica.
Whoa! Oh, whoopsie!
Oh, my God.
Morty.
You look really nice tonight.
Wow, thanks.
I love you, Morty!
I love you so much it burns!
Oh, man!
I love you too, Jessica!
Is this punk bothering you,
Jessica?
Leave him alone, jerk!
I'm in love with him!
He is more man than you will
ever be!
d This is about d
d flu awareness d
d got to be aware of the flu in d
d the air-ness d
d yo, I'm a flu-hating rapper d
Oh, man, Morty.
I'm really sorry.
Oh, well, no problem, Brad.
There's something special
about you, Morty so special.
- Mmm, yeah.
- Whoa, take it easy!
Get your hands off of him!
- Back off!
- I'm trying to be with my man!
That's enough, Bradley!
We don't want you injuring your
ball-throwing arm.
Oh, come on, principal Vagina.
Never leave me, Morty.
Never!
Uh, sure.
I mean, of course not.
What do you think that was all
about?
Who cares? Just hold me.
Let me go! I love you, Morty!
Let go of me!
Morty!
She's gonna be alone
with that guy all night.
Yeah, dad, digging
around the insides of horses.
It's not a very
romantic setting.
Well, Summer, there's
always the possibility
that she made the
whole work thing up.
Maybe Davin's digging
around in her insides.
Grandpa, so gross!
You're talking about my mom.
Well, she's my daughter, Summer.
I outrank you.
Or family means nothing, in
which case don't play that card.
She's not responding
to my texts!
Careful, dad.
Jealousy turns women off.
Well, isn't that convenient?
Not for the men they
cheat on, no.
Okay, I'm... going to
go out... for some ice cream.
And maybe stop by the
hospital... to support my wife...
with my confidence.
- God, grandpa, you're such a dick.
- I'm sorry, Summer.
Your opinion means very little
to me.
How come you're not at this stupid
dance everyone loves so much?
Screw that.
I don't want to get sick.
- It's flu season.
- It is?
- Yeah.
- Uh-oh.
Please just let this work out.
Do it, Morty. Do it.
Rip my clothes off and mate with
me for life!
Um...
Can we maybe go
somewhere more private?
Jessica, get a hold of yourself!
You don't deserve to carry
Morty's genes.
d I love Morty d
d and I hope Morty loves me d
d I'd like to wrap my arms d
d around him d
d and feel him inside me d
Oh, crap.
Morty!
Morty, come on!
We got to get you out of here.
You're not gonna believe this,
because it usually never happens,
but I made a mistake.
Come on, Morty.
We got to get out of here.
Morty!
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine!
Oh, good.
If anything ever happened to
you, I would kill myself.
I love you bad, mo-mo!
Morty, the principal and I
have discussed it,
and we're both insecure enough
to agree to a three-way!
I didn't realize when
I gave you that serum
that Jessica had
the flu, you know,
that might have been valuable
information for me, Morty.
What the hell is going on, Rick?
What does it look like?
The serum is piggybacking
on the virus.
It's gone airborne, Morty.
Oh, crap.
What are we gonna do, Rick?
It's gonna be fine,
Morty, relax.
I whipped up and antidote.
It's based on praying-mantis
You know, praying mantises are the
exact opposite of voles, Morty.
I mean, they they mate once, and then
they, you know,
...decapitate the partner.
I mean, it's a whole ritual.
It's really gruesome and totally
opposite.
There's no love at all.
I basically mixed this with
a more contagious flu virus.
It should neutralize the whole
thing, Morty.
It'll all be over very shortly.
Morty!
Uh, by the way, Morty, I know
you didn't ask or anything, but...
I'm not interested in having sex
with you.
These serums, they don't work on
anybody related to you genetically.
Morty!
Okay, well, sometimes, science
is more art than science, Morty.
A lot of people don't get that.
Come on. Are you kidding me?
Hello!
Morty!
You're not Morty!
Bring us Morty!
Nobody's killing me until after I
catch my wife with another man.
I had sex with Billy.
But you were already pregnant!
Yeah, so what's the worst
that could happen?
We interrupt "pregnant baby"
with breaking news.
Come on.
This just in; Morty Smith's
whereabouts are still unknown.
What the hell?
The only thing that is known
is... how cute he is.
I love him so much, I want to make
love to him and then eat his head.
I love him more than you do,
Harold!
You wish, you stupid bitch!
Morty's mine!
Meant to be together!
Morty!
Where is Morty?
Oh, my God, Rick.
The whole world is infected!
Yeah, it's pretty wild
how fast that spread.
I've really outdone myself.
Outdone yourself?!
Are you kidding me, Rick?
This is not okay!
Not only do they all want to
have sex with me,
but, you know, now they
want to eat me afterwards!
Yeah, I don't know what
I was thinking.
Mantises are they
opposite of voles?
I mean, obviously, DNA's a little
more complicated than that.
You know what, though, Morty?
This right here's gonna do the
trick, baby.
It's koala mixed with
rattlesnake, chimpanzee, cactus,
shark, golden retriever, and
just a smidge of dinosaur.
Should add up to normal
humanity.
That doesn't make
any sense, Rick.
How does that add up to normal
humanity?
What, Morty, you want
me to show you my math?
I'm sorry are you the scientist
or are you the kid that
wanted to get laid?
Well, I'm glad we saved
all those horses,
but I'm almost sorry
we're finished.
Yes, it's satisfying work.
Unh-unh-unh, it's, uh
it's more than the work.
I love being in that sterilized
room, sealed off from the world.
It's the only time I can really
think... and feel.
Hmm, uh, what are you doing?
I'm playing African dream pop.
What do you do after
a long night?
Oh, ha, um, hey,
I'd better get going.
Um, Jerry's been texting some
pretty high-maintenance stuff.
Beth...
What is it, Davin?
Just once, I'd like to know...
...what it was like to give
your son a bath.
What?!
What does Morty's
skin smell like?
How soft...
How soft are his privates?
Let go of me, Davin!
Take me to Morty.
You're not Morty.
No.
I'm Mr. Crowbar, and this is my
friend, who is also a crowbar.
That's... stupid.
Yeah?
Well, look where
being smart got you.
Jerry! Thank God!
God?
God's turning people into insect
monsters, Beth.
I'm the one beating
them to death.
Thank me.
Thank you, Jerry.
Thank you.
Take a good look down
there, Morty, and soak it in,
because, you know, once I pull this
lever, it's all back to normal.
Just do it already.
Well, technically, Morty,
there's no rush.
I mean, you know, once it's
fixed, it's done.
It's fixed.
You know, we could we could
just enjoy it for a little bit.
I mean, look at how crazy it is.
I mean, Morty,
when's the next time you're gonna see
something like this?
I mean, soak it in, you know?
It's it's pretty neat.
- It's pretty interesting.
- That's it, Rick!
I'm pulling the lever.
What do we have here, Morty?
Looks like I was right and you
were wrong, huh?
I bet you feel pretty stupid
right about now, huh?
I bet you feel like the
world's smallest man
that you were doubting me
about this whole thing, Morty.
Oh, Rick, something's not right.
Yeah, you.
- You're not right ever.
- No, no!
Look, you idiot!
Bet you're loving this, Morty.
This must be the best day of
your life.
You get to be the mayor of
"I told you" town.
You're welcome.
Hold on.
I wish that shotgun
was my penis.
If it were, you could
call me Ernest Hemingway.
I don't get it, and I
don't need to.
Mom! Dad!
- Summer!
- Where's Morty?
- I don't know.
Do you think grandpa Rick had
something to do with this?
It's not fair to
assume that, Summer.
Oh, not fair?
Give me a break.
He is a selfish, irresponsible
ass, and he left my mother.
A real man stands by his woman.
Tchoo-tchoo-tchoo. Tchoo-tchoo.
Boy, Morty, I really cronenberged
the world up, didn't I?
We got a whole planet
of cronenbergs
walking around down
there, Morty.
At least they're not in love
with you anymore, though.
That's a huge step in the right
direction.
Oh, my God!
It's a living nightmare!
How could you be so
irresponsible, Rick?
Me irresponsible?!
All I wanted you to do was
hand me a screwdriver, Morty!
You're the one who wanted me
to buckle down
and make you up a... roofie-juice
serum so you could roofie that
poor girl at your school.
I mean, are you kidding me, Morty?
You're gonna try to take the
high road on this one?
You're a little creep, Morty.
You're you're just a little
creepy... creep person.
All right, fine.
I should have just listened to you
when you refused to make the serum.
I'm willing to accept my part of
the blame for this, Rick.
But I'll tell you something
you know what?
You got to accept your part of
the blame!
I'm not the one who fouled up
the serum!
I'm not the one who
haphazardly, you know,
mixed a bunch of nonsense together
and created a bunch of cronenbergs!
You got to fix this, Rick!
All right, all right, Morty.
You know, we are in a
pretty deep hole, here,
but I do have one emergency solution that
I can use that'll kind of put
everything back to normal,
relatively speaking.
Here, Morty, put this on while I
do a little bit of scouting.
Wow, Rick, I got to say,
you really pulled a rabbit
out of your hat this time.
I mean, I really thought
that the whole place
was gonna be
messed up for good, but here,
you did it... you figured out that
crazy solution, like you always do.
Whoo!
That's some great luck.
Come on, Morty.
Luck had nothing to do with it.
I'm great.
That's the real reason.
Now, Morty, what do you say,
buddy?
Will you hand me a screwdriver
so I can finish my ionic dis
defibulizer?
Sure thing, Rick.
Here's a screwdriver.
All right, Morty.
Thank you very much.
We got one screw turn... and two
screw turns... and...
All right, Morty, here we are.
Oh, my God, Rick!
Is that us?!
We're dead!
What is going on, Rick?
I'm freaking out!
Calm down, Morty!
Look at me! Calm down, Morty!
No, I can't deal with this!
- Calm yourself, Morty.
- I can't deal with this, Rick!
- Calm down, Morty.
- This can't be real!
You got to calm down, Morty.
We're ripped apart!
Shut up and listen to me!
It's fine. Everything is fine.
There's an infinite number of
realities, Morty,
and in a few dozen of
those, I got lucky and
turned everything back to
normal.
I just had to find one
of those realities
in which we also happen
to both die around this time.
Now we can just slip into the
place of our dead selves in this
reality and everything will be
fine.
We're not skipping a beat,
Morty.
- Now, help me with these bodies.
- This is insane.
Look, Morty, I'll grab
myself, you grab yourself, okay?
I mean, that seems
fair to me I mean,
that seems like a
fair way to divvy it up.
Rick, what about the
reality we left behind?
What about the reality where
Hitler cured cancer, Morty?
The answer is don't
think about it.
It's not like we can do this
every week, anyways.
We get three or four more of
these, tops.
Now, pick up your dead self and
come on.
Haste makes waste.
I don't suppose you've
considered this detail,
but obviously, if I hadn't screwed
up as much as I did,
we'd be these guys right now,
so, again, you're welcome.
d Look on down from the bridge d
d there's still fountains down there d
d look on down from the bridge d
d it's still raining up here d
d everybody seems so d
d far away from me d
d everybody just d
d wants to be free d
d look away from the sky d
d it's no different when you're d
d leaving home d
d I can't be the same d
d thing to you now d
d I'm just gone d
d just gone d
d how could I say goodbye? d
d How could I say goodbye? d
You know, the thing
about a shark...
He's got lifeless eyes...
black eyes, like a doll's eyes.
When he comes at ya, he doesn't
seem to be living until he bites ya,
and then the the blood,
and the red, and the water...
You ever wonder what happened to
Rick and Morty?
Sometimes.
But, I'm ashamed to admit, now that
they're gone, I'm finally happy.
Here we are, cronenberg Morty,
a reality where everyone in the world got
genetically cronenberged.
We'll fit right in,
cronenberg Morty.
It'll be like we never even left
cronenberg world.
Yeah, cronenberg Rick, but, you know,
I'm gonna miss cronenberg world,
because everyone was
cronenberged all along
like us from the
beginning, you know?
I mean, I wish we hadn't
genetically ruined cronenberg world
beyond repair like we did,
you know, and turned everyone
into regular, normal people just
walking around.
Don't you worry about that sort
of thing, cronenberg Morty.
Let's go make ourselves at home,
huh?
Sync & corrections by XhmikosR
www.addic7ed.com